{
  "Chapter 1": {
    "1": {
      "Question": "1.She hadn\u2019t eaten all day, and by the time she got home she was______.",
      "a": {
        "option": "blighted",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. cause to suffer a blight\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. affected by blight; anything that mars or prevents growth or prosperity\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "confutative",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. able to be refuted\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "ravenous",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. extremely hungry\n2. devouring or craving food in great quantities\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "ostentatious",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. intended to attract notice and impress others\n2. (of a display\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "blissful",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. completely happy and contented\n"
      },
      "Answer": "c. Ravenous (adj.) means extremely hungry."
    },
    "2": {
      "Question": "2.The movie offended many of the parents of its younger viewers byincluding unnecessary ______ in the dialogue.Chapter 1",
      "a": {
        "option": "vulgarity",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the quality of lacking taste and refinement\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "verbosity",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. an expressive style that uses excessive or empty words\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "vocalizations",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the sound made by the vibration of vocal folds modified by the resonance of the vocal tract\n2. the use of uttered sounds for auditory communication\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "garishness",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. tasteless showiness\n2. strident color or excessive ornamentation\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "tonality",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. any of 24 major or minor diatonic scales that provide the tonal framework for a piece of music\n"
      },
      "Answer": "a. Vulgarity (n.) means offensive speech or conduct."
    },
    "3": {
      "Question": "3.His neighbors found his ______ manner bossy and irritating, andthey stopped inviting him to backyard barbeques.",
      "a": {
        "option": "insentient",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. devoid of feeling and consciousness and animation\n2. or insensate\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "magisterial",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. of or relating to a magistrate\n2. offensively self-assured or given to exercising usually unwarranted power\n3. used of a person's appearance or behavior; befitting an eminent person\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "reparatory",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "restorative",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a medicine that strengthens and invigorates\n2. a device for treating injury or disease\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. tending to impart new life and vigor to\n2. promoting recuperation\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "modest",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. marked by simplicity; having a humble opinion of yourself\n2. not large but sufficient in size or amount\n3. free from pomp or affectation\n4. not offensive to sexual mores in conduct or appearance\n5. low or inferior in station or quality\n6. humble in spirit or manner; suggesting retiring mildness or even cowed submissiveness\n7. relatively moderate, limited, or small\n"
      },
      "Answer": "b. Magisterial (adj.) means overbearing or offensively self-assured."
    },
    "4": {
      "Question": "4.Steven is always ______ about showing up for work because hefeels that tardiness is a sign of irresponsibility.",
      "a": {
        "option": "legible",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. (of handwriting, print, etc.\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "tolerable",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. capable of being borne or endured\n2. about average; acceptable\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "punctual",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. acting or arriving or performed exactly at the time appointed\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "literal",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a mistake in printed matter resulting from mechanical failures of some kind\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. being or reflecting the essential or genuine character of something\n2. without interpretation or embellishment\n3. limited to the explicit meaning of a word or text\n4. avoiding embellishment or exaggeration (used for emphasis\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "belligerent",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. someone who fights (or is fighting\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. characteristic of an enemy or one eager to fight\n2. engaged in war\n3. or warring\n"
      },
      "Answer": "c. Punctual (adj.) means arriving exactly on time."
    },
    "5": {
      "Question": "5.Candace would ______ her little sister into an argument by teasingher and calling her names.",
      "a": {
        "option": "advocate",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a person who pleads for a cause or propounds an idea\n2. a lawyer who pleads cases in court\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. push for something\n2. speak, plead, or argue in favor of\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "provoke",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. call forth (emotions, feelings, and responses\n2. evoke or provoke to appear or occur\n3. provide the needed stimulus for\n4. annoy continually or chronically\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "perforate",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. make a hole into or between, as for ease of separation\n2. pass into or through, often by overcoming resistance\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. having a hole cut through\n"
      },
      "d": { "option": "lamente", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "expunge",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. remove by erasing or crossing out or as if by drawing a line\n"
      },
      "Answer": "b. To provoke (v.) is to incite anger or resentment; to call forth afeeling or action."
    },
    "6": {
      "Question": "6.The dress Ariel wore ______ with small, glassy beads, creating ashimmering effect.",
      "a": {
        "option": "titillated",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. touch (a body part\n2. excite pleasurably or erotically\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. feeling mild pleasurable excitement\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "reiterated",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. to say, state, or perform again\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "scintillated",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. give off\n2. reflect brightly\n3. emit or reflect light in a flickering manner\n4. physics: fluoresce momentarily when struck by a charged particle or high-energy photon\n5. be lively or brilliant or exhibit virtuosity\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "enthralled",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. hold spellbound\n2. hold spellbound\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. filled with wonder and delight\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "striated",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. mark with striae or striations\n"
      },
      "Answer": "c. To scintillate (v.) means to emit or send forth sparks or little\ufb02ashes of light, creating a shimmering effect; to sparkle."
    },
    "7": {
      "Question": "7.Being able to afford this luxury car will ______ getting a better-paying job.2",
      "a": {
        "option": "maximize",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. make as big or large as possible\n2. make the most of\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "recombinant",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a cell or organism in which genetic recombination has occurred\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. of or relating to recombinant DNA\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "reiterate",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. to say, state, or perform again\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "necessitate",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. require as useful, just, or proper\n2. cause to be a concomitant\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "reciprocate",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. act, feel, or give mutually or in return\n2. alternate the direction of motion of\n"
      },
      "Answer": "d. To necessitate (v.) means to make necessary, especially as a result."
    },
    "8": {
      "Question": "8.Levina unknowingly ______ the thief by holding open the elevator",
      "d": {
        "option": "sanctioned",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. give sanction to\n2. give authority or permission to\n3. give religious sanction to, such as through on oath\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. conforming to orthodox or recognized rules\n2. formally approved and invested with legal authority\n3. established by authority; given authoritative approval\n"
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "coerced",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. to cause to do through pressure or necessity, by physical, moral or intellectual means\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "proclaimed",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. declare formally; declare someone to be something; of titles\n2. state or announce\n3. affirm or declare as an attribute or quality of\n4. praise, glorify, or honor\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. declared publicly; made widely known\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "abetted",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. assist or encourage, usually in some wrongdoing\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "solicited",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. make a solicitation or entreaty for something; request urgently or persistently\n2. make amorous advances towards\n3. approach with an offer of sexual favors\n4. incite, move, or persuade to some act of lawlessness or insubordination\n5. make a solicitation or petition for something desired\n"
      },
      "Answer": "c. To abet (v.) means to assist, encourage, urge, or aid, usually anact of wrongdoing."
    },
    "9": {
      "Question": "9.Shakespeare, a(n) ______ writer, entertained audiences by writingmany tragic and comic plays.",
      "a": {
        "option": "numeric",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. of or relating to or denoting numbers\n2. measured or expressed in numbers\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "obstinate",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. persist stubbornly\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. tenaciously unwilling or marked by tenacious unwillingness to yield\n2. stubbornly persistent in wrongdoing\n3. resistant to guidance or discipline\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "dutiful",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. willingly obedient out of a sense of duty and respect\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "proli\ufb01c",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "generic",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. wine that does not meet the minimum qualifications and standards for use of a designation by appellation of origin (where the grapes are grown\n2. made-up\n3. such as `vin rouge', `vino rosso', `rotwein', `red wine', etc.\n4. as `vin ordinaire', `vin de table', `vino da tavola', `tafelwein', `table wine', etc.\n5. any product that can be sold without a brand name\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. relating to or common to or descriptive of all members of a genus\n2. (of drugs\n3. applicable to an entire class or group\n"
      },
      "Answer": "d. Proli\ufb01c (adj.) means abundantly creative."
    },
    "10": {
      "Question": ".10.I had the ______ experience of sitting next to an over-talkativepassenger on my \ufb02ight home from Brussels.",
      "a": {
        "option": "satisfactory",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. giving satisfaction\n2. meeting requirements\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "commendable",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. worthy of high praise\nAdverb meaning(s):\n1. in an admirable manner\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "galling",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. become or make sore by or as if by rubbing\n2. irritate or vex\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. causing irritation or annoyance\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "acceptable",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. worthy of acceptance or satisfactory\n2. judged to be in conformity with approved usage\n3. meeting requirements\n4. adequate for the purpose\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "acute",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a mark placed above a vowel to indicate pronunciation\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. having or experiencing a rapid onset and short but severe course\n2. extremely sharp or severe\n3. having or demonstrating ability to recognize or draw fine distinctions\n4. of an angle; less than 90 degrees\n5. ending in a sharp point\n6. of critical importance and consequence\n7. or critical\n"
      },
      "Answer": "c. Galling (adj.) means irritating, annoying, or exasperating."
    },
    "11": {
      "Question": ".11.Prince Phillip had to choose: marry the woman he loved and ______his right to the throne, or marry Lady Fiona and inherit the crown.",
      "a": {
        "option": "reprimand",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. an act or expression of criticism and censure\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. rebuke formally\n2. censure severely or angrily\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "upbraid",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. express criticism towards\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "abdicate",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. give up, such as power, as of monarchs and emperors, or duties and obligations\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "winnow",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the act of separating grain from chaff\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. separate the chaff from grain by using air currents\n2. blow on\n3. select desirable parts from a group or list\n4. blow away or off with a current of air\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "extol",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. praise, glorify, or honor\n"
      },
      "Answer": "c. To abdicate (v.) means to formally relinquish or surrender power,of\ufb01ce, or responsibility."
    },
    "12": {
      "Question": ".12.If you will not do your work of your own ______, I have no choice",
      "b": {
        "option": "coercion",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the act of compelling by force of authority\n2. using force to cause something to occur\n"
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "predilection",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a predisposition in favor of something\n2. a strong liking\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "excursion",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a journey taken for pleasure\n2. wandering from the main path of a journey\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "volition",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the capability of conscious choice and decision and intention\n2. the act of making a choice\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "infusion",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a solution obtained by steeping or soaking a substance (usually in water\n2. the process of extracting certain active properties (as a drug from a plant\n3. usually in water\n4. (medicine\n5. a fluid or drug or electrolyte\n6. as by gravitational force\n7. the act of infusing or introducing a certain modifying element or quality\n"
      },
      "Answer": "d. Volition (n.) means accord; an act or exercise of will."
    },
    "13": {
      "Question": ".13.After sitting in the sink for several days, the dirty, food-encrusted",
      "d": {
        "option": "perforated",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. make a hole into or between, as for ease of separation\n2. pass into or through, often by overcoming resistance\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. having a hole cut through\n2. having a number or series of holes\n"
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "malodorous",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. having an unpleasant smell\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "prevalent",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. most frequent or common\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "imposing",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. compel to behave in a certain way\n2. impose something unpleasant\n3. impose and collect\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. impressive in appearance\n2. used of a person's appearance or behavior; befitting an eminent person\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "emphatic",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. spoken with emphasis\n2. sudden and strong\n3. forceful and definite in expression or action\n"
      },
      "Answer": "a. Malodorous (adj.) means having a foul-smelling odor."
    },
    "14": {
      "Question": ".14.Giulia soon discovered the source of the ______ smell in the room:the closet.",
      "a": {
        "option": "quaint",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. strange in an interesting or pleasing way\n2. very strange or unusual; odd or even incongruous in character or appearance\n3. attractively old-fashioned (but not necessarily authentic\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "fastidious",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. giving careful attention to detail; hard to please; excessively concerned with cleanliness\n2. having complicated nutritional requirements; especially growing only in special artificial cultures\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "clandestine",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. conducted with or marked by hidden aims or methods\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "laconic",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. brief and to the point; effectively cut short\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "fetid",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. offensively malodorous\n"
      },
      "Answer": "e. Fetid (adj.) means having a foul or offensive odor, putrid."
    },
    "15": {
      "Question": ".15.After making ______ remarks to the President, the reporter wasnot invited to return to the White House pressroom.",
      "a": {
        "option": "hospitable",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. favorable to life and growth\n2. disposed to treat guests and strangers with cordiality and generosity\n3. having an open mind\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "itinerant",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a laborer who moves from place to place as demanded by employment\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. traveling from place to place to work\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "enterprising",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. marked by imagination, initiative, and readiness to undertake new projects\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "chivalrous",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. being attentive to women like an ideal knight\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "irreverent",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. showing lack of due respect or veneration\n2. characterized by a lightly pert and exuberant quality\n3. not revering god\n"
      },
      "Answer": "e. Irreverent (adj.) means lacking respect or seriousness; notreverent."
    },
    "16": {
      "Question": ".16.With her ______ eyesight, Krystyna spotted a trio of deer on thehillside and she reduced the speed of her car.4",
      "a": {
        "option": "inferior",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. one of lesser rank or station or quality\n2. a character or symbol set or printed or written beneath or slightly below and to the side of another character\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. of or characteristic of low rank or importance\n2. of low or inferior quality\n3. written or printed below and to one side of another character\n4. having an orbit between the sun and the Earth's orbit\n5. lower than a given reference point\n6. falling short of some prescribed norm\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "keen",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a funeral lament sung with loud wailing\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. express grief verbally\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. having or demonstrating ability to recognize or draw fine distinctions\n2. intense or sharp\n3. very good\n4. painful as if caused by a sharp instrument\n5. having a sharp cutting edge or point\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "impressionable",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. easily impressed or influenced\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "ductile",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. easily influenced\n2. capable of being shaped or bent or drawn out\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "conspiratorial",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. relating to or characteristic of conspiracy or conspirators\n"
      },
      "Answer": "b. Keen (adj.) means being extremely sensitive or responsive;having strength of perception.501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    },
    "17": {
      "Question": ".17.With a(n) ______ grin, the boy quickly slipped the candy into hispocket without his mother\u2019s knowledge.",
      "a": {
        "option": "jaundiced",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. distort adversely\n2. affect with, or as if with, jaundice\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. affected by jaundice which causes yellowing of skin etc\n2. showing or affected by prejudice or envy or distaste\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "nefarious",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. extremely wicked\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "stereotypical",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. lacking spontaneity or originality or individuality\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "sentimental",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. given to or marked by sentiment or sentimentality\n2. effusively or insincerely emotional\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "impartial",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. showing lack of favoritism\n2. free from undue bias or preconceived opinions\n"
      },
      "Answer": "b. Nefarious (adj.) means wicked, vicious, or evil."
    },
    "18": {
      "Question": ".18.Her ______ display of tears at work did not impress her new boss,who felt she should try to control her emotions.",
      "a": {
        "option": "maudlin",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. effusively or insincerely emotional\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "meritorious",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. deserving reward or praise\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "precarious",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. affording no ease or reassurance\n2. fraught with danger\n3. not secure; beset with difficulties\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "plausible",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. apparently reasonable and credible, and therefore convincing\n2. given to or characterized by presenting specious arguments\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "schematic",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. diagram of an electrical or mechanical system\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. represented in simplified or symbolic form\n"
      },
      "Answer": "a. Maudlin (adj.) means excessively and weakly sentimental ortearfully emotional."
    },
    "19": {
      "Question": ".19.Johan argued, \u201cIf you know about a crime but don\u2019t report it, you",
      "a": {
        "option": "acquitted",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. pronounce not guilty of criminal charges\n2. behave in a certain manner\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. declared not guilty of a specific offense or crime; legally blameless\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "steadfast",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. marked by firm determination or resolution; not shakable\n2. firm and dependable especially in loyalty\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "tenuous",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. having thin consistency\n2. very thin in gauge or diameter\n3. lacking substance or significance\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "complicit",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "nulli\ufb01ed",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Complicit (adj.) means participating in or associated with aquestionable act or a crime."
    },
    "20": {
      "Question": ".20.The authorities, fearing a ______ of their power, called for amilitary state in the hopes of restoring order.",
      "a": {
        "option": "subversion",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. destroying someone's (or some group's\n2. the act of subverting; as overthrowing or destroying a legally constituted government\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "premonition",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a feeling of evil to come\n2. an early warning about a future event\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "predilection",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a predisposition in favor of something\n2. a strong liking\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "infusion",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a solution obtained by steeping or soaking a substance (usually in water\n2. the process of extracting certain active properties (as a drug from a plant\n3. usually in water\n4. (medicine\n5. a fluid or drug or electrolyte\n6. as by gravitational force\n7. the act of infusing or introducing a certain modifying element or quality\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "inversion",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the layer of air near the earth is cooler than an overlying layer\n2. abnormal condition in which an organ is turned inward or inside out (as when the upper part of the uterus is pulled into the cervical canal after childbirth\n3. a chemical process in which the direction of optical rotation of a substance is reversed from dextrorotatory to levorotary or vice versa\n4. (genetics\n5. the reversal of the normal order of words\n6. (counterpoint\n7. a term formerly used to mean taking on the gender role of the opposite sex\n8. turning upside down; setting on end\n9. the act of turning inside out\n"
      },
      "Answer": "a. Subversion (n.) means an overthrow, as from the foundation."
    },
    "21": {
      "Question": ".21.The story\u2019s bitter antagonist felt such great ______ for all of the other",
      "c": {
        "option": "reciprocation",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the act of making or doing something in return\n2. alternating back-and-forth movement\n3. mutual interaction; the activity of reciprocating or exchanging (especially information\n"
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "insurgence",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. an organized rebellion aimed at overthrowing a constituted government through the use of subversion and armed conflict\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "malevolence",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. wishing evil to others\n2. the quality of threatening evil\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "declamation",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. vehement oratory\n2. recitation of a speech from memory with studied gestures and intonation as an exercise in elocution or rhetoric\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "preference",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a strong liking\n2. a predisposition in favor of something\n3. the right or chance to choose\n4. grant of favor or advantage to one over another (especially to a country or countries in matters of international trade, such as levying duties\n"
      },
      "Answer": "b. Malevolence (n.) means ill will or malice toward others; hate."
    },
    "22": {
      "Question": ".22.It is dif\ufb01cult to believe that charging 20% on an outstanding credit",
      "c": {
        "option": "novice",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. someone who has entered a religious order but has not taken final vows\n2. someone new to a field or activity\n"
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "bankruptcy",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a state of complete lack of some abstract property\n2. inability to discharge all your debts as they come due\n3. a legal process intended to insure equality among the creditors of a corporation declared to be insolvent\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "usury",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. an exorbitant or unlawful rate of interest\n2. the act of lending money at an exorbitant rate of interest\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "kleptomania",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. an irresistible impulse to steal in the absence of any economic motive\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "\ufb02agrancy",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Usury (n.) is the lending of money at exorbitant interest rates."
    },
    "23": {
      "Question": ".23.The ______ weather patterns of the tropical island meant touristshad to carry both umbrellas and sunglasses.",
      "a": {
        "option": "impertinent",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. characterized by a lightly pert and exuberant quality\n2. not pertinent to the matter under consideration\n3. improperly forward or bold\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "supplicant",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. someone who prays to God\n2. one praying humbly for something\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. humbly entreating\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "preeminent",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. greatest in importance or degree or significance or achievement\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "illustrative",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. clarifying by use of examples\n2. serving to demonstrate\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "kaleidoscopic",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. continually shifting or rapidly changing\n"
      },
      "Answer": "e. Kaleidoscopic (adj.) means continually changing or quicklyshifting."
    },
    "24": {
      "Question": ".24.Wedding ceremonies often include the exchange of ______ ringsto symbolize the couple\u2019s promises to each other.",
      "a": {
        "option": "hirsute",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. having or covered with hair\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "acrimonious",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. marked by strong resentment or cynicism\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "plaintive",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. expressing sorrow\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "deciduous",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. (of plants and shrubs\n2. (of teeth, antlers, etc.\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "votive",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. dedicated in fulfillment of a vow\n"
      },
      "Answer": "e. Votive (adj.) means dedicated by a vow."
    },
    "25": {
      "Question": ".25.Kym was ______ in choosing her friends, so her parties were6",
      "a": {
        "option": "indispensable",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. not to be dispensed with; essential\n2. absolutely necessary; vitally necessary\n3. unavoidable\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "indiscriminate",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. failing to make or recognize distinctions\n2. not marked by fine distinctions\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "commensurate",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. corresponding in size or degree or extent\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "propulsive",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. having the power to propel\n2. tending to or capable of propelling\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "indisputable",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. not open to question; obviously true\n2. impossible to doubt or dispute\n3. or sure\n"
      },
      "Answer": "b. Indiscriminate (adj.) means not discriminating or choosingrandomly; haphazard; without distinction.8501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    }
  },
  "Chapter 2": {
    "26": {
      "Question": ".26.Phillip\u2019s ______ tone endeared him to his comical friends, butirritated his serious father.",
      "a": {
        "option": "aloof",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. remote in manner\nAdverb meaning(s):\n1. in an aloof manner\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "jesting",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. tell a joke; speak humorously\n2. act in a funny or teasing way\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. characterized by jokes and good humor\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "grave",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. death of a person\n2. a place for the burial of a corpse (especially beneath the ground and marked by a tombstone\n3. a mark (`\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. shape (a material like stone or wood\n2. carve, cut, or etch into a material or surface\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. dignified and somber in manner or character and committed to keeping promises\n2. causing fear or anxiety by threatening great harm\n3. of great gravity or crucial import; requiring serious thought\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "earnest",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. something of value given by one person to another to bind a contract\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. characterized by a firm and humorless belief in the validity of your opinions\n2. sincerely earnest\n3. not distracted by anything unrelated to the goal\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "conservative",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a person who is reluctant to accept changes and new ideas\n2. a member of a Conservative Party\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. resistant to change, particularly in relation to politics or religion\n2. having social or political views favoring conservatism\n3. avoiding excess\n4. unimaginatively conventional\n5. conforming to the standards and conventions of the middle class\n"
      },
      "Answer": "b. Jesting (adj.) means characterized by making jests; joking;playful."
    },
    "27": {
      "Question": ".27.Brian\u2019s pale Irish skin was ______ to burn if he spent too muchtime in the sun.Chapter 2",
      "a": {
        "option": "prone",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. having a tendency (to\n2. lying face downward\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "urbane",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. showing a high degree of refinement and the assurance that comes from wide social experience\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "eminent",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. standing above others in quality or position\n2. of imposing height; especially standing out above others\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "erect",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. construct, build, or erect\n2. cause to rise up\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. upright in position or posture\n2. of sexual organs; stiff and rigid\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "daunted",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. cause to lose courage\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. caused to show discomposure\n"
      },
      "Answer": "a. Prone (adj.) means a tendency or inclination to something."
    },
    "28": {
      "Question": ".28.A fan of historical \ufb01ction, Joline is now reading a novel aboutslavery in the ______ South.",
      "a": {
        "option": "decorous",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. characterized by propriety and dignity and good taste in manners and conduct\n2. according with custom or propriety\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "rogue",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a deceitful and unreliable scoundrel\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "droll",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. comical in an odd or whimsical manner\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "antebellum",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. belonging to a period before a war especially the American Civil War\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "onerous",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. not easily borne; wearing\n"
      },
      "Answer": "d. Antebellum (adj.) means belonging to the period before a war,especially the American Civil War."
    },
    "29": {
      "Question": ".29.Over the years the Wilsons slowly ______ upon the Jacksons\u2019property, moving the stone markers that divided their lots farther",
      "a": {
        "option": "encroached",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. advance beyond the usual limit\n2. impinge or infringe upon\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "jettisoned",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. throw away, of something encumbering\n2. throw as from an airplane\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "conjoined",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. make contact or come together\n2. take in marriage\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. consisting of two or more associated entities\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "repudiated",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. cast off\n2. refuse to acknowledge, ratify, or recognize as valid\n3. refuse to recognize or pay\n4. reject as untrue, unfounded, or unjust\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "teemed",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. be teeming, be abuzz\n2. move in large numbers\n"
      },
      "Answer": "a. To encroach (v.) means to gradually or stealthily take the rightsor possessions of another; to advance beyond proper or formallimits; trespass."
    },
    "30": {
      "Question": ".30.Mary became ______ at typing because she practiced every day forsix months.",
      "a": {
        "option": "pro\ufb01cient",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "re\ufb02ective",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "dormant",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. in a condition of biological rest or suspended animation\n2. (of e.g. volcanos\n3. lying with head on paws as if sleeping\n4. inactive but capable of becoming active\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "redundant",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. more than is needed, desired, or required\n2. or unnecessary\n3. repetition of same sense in different words\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "valiant",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. having or showing valor\n"
      },
      "Answer": "a. Pro\ufb01cient (adj.) means well versed in any business or branch oflearning; adept."
    },
    "31": {
      "Question": ".31.To \ufb01nd out what her husband bought for her birthday, Susan10",
      "a": {
        "option": "prescribe",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. issue commands or orders for\n2. recommend as beneficial\n3. (medicine\n4. a treatment, medicine, etc.\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "revere",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. American silversmith remembered for his midnight ride (celebrated in a poem by Longfellow\n2. 1735-1818\n3. a lapel on a woman's garment; turned back to show the reverse side\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. love unquestioningly and uncritically or to excess; venerate as an idol\n2. regard with feelings of respect and reverence; consider hallowed or exalted or be in awe of\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "probe",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. an inquiry into unfamiliar or questionable activities\n2. a flexible slender surgical instrument with a blunt end that is used to explore wounds or body cavities\n3. an exploratory action or expedition\n4. an investigation conducted using a flexible surgical instrument to explore an injury or a body cavity\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. question or examine thoroughly and closely\n2. examine physically with or as if with a probe\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "alienate",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. arouse hostility or indifference in where there had formerly been love, affection, or friendliness\n2. transfer property or ownership\n3. make withdrawn or isolated or emotionally dissociated\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "converge",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. be adjacent or come together\n2. approach a limit as the number of terms increases without limit\n3. move or draw together at a certain location\n4. come together so as to form a single product\n"
      },
      "Answer": "b. To probe (v.) is to examine thoroughly; tentatively survey."
    },
    "32": {
      "Question": ".32.Juan\u2019s friends found him in a ______ mood after he learned hewould be homecoming king.",
      "a": {
        "option": "jovial",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. full of or showing high-spirited merriment\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "stealthy",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. marked by quiet and caution and secrecy; taking pains to avoid being observed\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "paltry",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. not worth considering\n2. contemptibly small in amount\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "gullible",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. naive and easily deceived or tricked\n2. easily tricked because of being too trusting\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "depleted",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. use up (resources or materials\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. no longer sufficient\n"
      },
      "Answer": "a. Jovial (adj.) means showing hearty good cheer; marked with thespirit of jolly merriment."
    },
    "33": {
      "Question": ".33.His suit of armor made the knight ______ to his enemy\u2019s attack,",
      "a": {
        "option": "vulnerable",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. susceptible to attack\n2. susceptible to criticism or persuasion or temptation\n3. capable of being wounded or hurt\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "churlish",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. rude and boorish\n2. having a bad disposition; surly\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "invulnerable",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. immune to attack; impregnable\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "static",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a crackling or hissing noise caused by electrical interference\n2. angry criticism\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. not in physical motion\n2. concerned with or producing or caused by static electricity\n3. showing little if any change\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "imprudent",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. not prudent or wise\n2. lacking wise self-restraint\n"
      },
      "Answer": "c. Invulnerable (adj.) means incapable of being damaged orwounded; unassailable or invincible."
    },
    "34": {
      "Question": ".34.Choosing a small, fuel-ef\ufb01cient car is a ______ purchase for arecent college graduate.",
      "a": {
        "option": "corrupt",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. corrupt morally or by intemperance or sensuality\n2. make illegal payments to in exchange for favors or influence\n3. place under suspicion or cast doubt upon\n4. alter from the original\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. lacking in integrity\n2. not straight; dishonest or immoral or evasive\n3. containing errors or alterations\n4. touched by rot or decay\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "tedious",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. so lacking in interest as to cause mental weariness\n2. using or containing too many words\n3. or windy\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "unhallowed",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. remove the consecration from a person or an object\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. not hallowed or consecrated\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "sardonic",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. disdainfully or ironically humorous; scornful and mocking\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "judicious",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. marked by the exercise of good judgment or common sense in practical matters\n"
      },
      "Answer": "e. Judicious (adj.) means being wise or prudent; showing goodjudgment; sensible."
    },
    "35": {
      "Question": ".35.Such a ______ violation of school policy should be punished bynothing less than expulsion.",
      "a": {
        "option": "copious",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. large in number or quantity (especially of discourse\n2. affording an abundant supply\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "\ufb02agrant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "raucous",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. unpleasantly loud and harsh\n2. disturbing the public peace; loud and rough\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "nominal",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a phrase that can function as the subject or object of a verb\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. relating to or constituting or bearing or giving a name\n2. insignificantly small; a matter of form only (`tokenish' is informal\n3. pertaining to a noun or to a word group that functions as a noun\n4. of, relating to, or characteristic of an amount that is not adjusted for inflation\n5. named; bearing the name of a specific person\n6. existing in name only\n7. or titular\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "morose",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. showing a brooding ill humor\n"
      },
      "Answer": "b. Flagrant (adj.) means conspicuously and outrageously bad,offensive, or reprehensible."
    },
    "36": {
      "Question": ".36.With all of the recent negative events in her life, she felt ______forces must be at work.",
      "a": {
        "option": "resurgent",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. rising again as to new life and vigor\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "premature",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. born after a gestation period of less than the normal time\n2. too soon or too hasty\n3. uncommonly early or before the expected time\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "malignant",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. dangerous to health; characterized by progressive and uncontrolled growth (especially of a tumor\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "punctilious",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. marked by precise accordance with details\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "antecedent",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. someone from whom you are descended (but usually more remote than a grandparent\n2. a preceding occurrence or cause or event\n3. anything that precedes something similar in time\n4. the referent of an anaphor; a phrase or clause that is referred to by an anaphoric pronoun\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. preceding in time or order\n"
      },
      "Answer": "c. Malignant (adj.) means disposed to cause distress or in\ufb02ictsuffering intentionally; inclining to produce death; an injuriousin\ufb01ltration."
    },
    "37": {
      "Question": ".37.The ______ rumors did a great deal of damage even though theyturned out to be false.",
      "a": {
        "option": "bemused",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. cause to be confused emotionally\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. deeply absorbed in thought\n2. perplexed by many conflicting situations or statements; filled with bewilderment\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "prosaic",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. not fanciful or imaginative\n2. lacking wit or imagination\n3. not challenging; dull and lacking excitement\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "apocryphal",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. being of questionable authenticity\n2. of or belonging to the Apocrypha\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "ebullient",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. joyously unrestrained\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "tantamount",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. being essentially equal to something\n"
      },
      "Answer": "c. Apocryphal (adj.) means of questionable authenticity or doubtfulauthority; \ufb01ctitious, false."
    },
    "38": {
      "Question": ".38.When her schoolwork got to be too much, Pam had a tendency to______, which always put her further behind.",
      "a": {
        "option": "dedicate",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. give entirely to a specific person, activity, or cause\n2. open to public use, as of a highway, park, or building\n3. inscribe or address by way of compliment\n4. set apart to sacred uses with solemn rites, of a church\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "rejuvenate",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. cause (a stream or river\n2. develop youthful topographical features\n3. make younger or more youthful\n4. return to life; get or give new life or energy\n5. become young again\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "ponder",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. reflect deeply on a subject\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "excel",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. distinguish oneself\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "procrastinate",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. postpone doing what one should be doing\n2. postpone or delay needlessly\n"
      },
      "Answer": "e. To procrastinate (v.) is to put off from day to day.501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    },
    "39": {
      "Question": ".39.Racha\u2019s glance was a ______ invitation to speak later in private",
      "a": {
        "option": "trecherous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "scintillating",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. give off\n2. reflect brightly\n3. emit or reflect light in a flickering manner\n4. physics: fluoresce momentarily when struck by a charged particle or high-energy photon\n5. be lively or brilliant or exhibit virtuosity\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. brilliantly clever\n2. marked by high spirits or excitement\n3. having brief brilliant points or flashes of light\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "tactful",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. having or showing a sense of what is fitting and considerate in dealing with others\n2. showing skill and sensitivity in dealing with people\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "tacit",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. implied by or inferred from actions or statements\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "taboo",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a prejudice (especially in Polynesia and other South Pacific islands\n2. an inhibition or ban resulting from social custom or emotional aversion\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. declare as sacred and forbidden\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. excluded from use or mention\n2. forbidden to profane use especially in South Pacific islands\n"
      },
      "Answer": "c. Tacit (adj.) means unspoken yet understood."
    },
    "40": {
      "Question": ".40.She reached the ______ of her career with her fourth novel, whichwon the Pulitzer Prize.",
      "a": {
        "option": "harbinger",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. something that precedes and indicates the approach of something or someone\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. foreshadow or presage\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "apogee",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a final climactic stage\n2. apoapsis in Earth orbit; the point in its orbit where a satellite is at the greatest distance from the Earth\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "metamorphosis",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the marked and rapid transformation of a larva into an adult that occurs in some animals\n2. a striking change in appearance or character or circumstances\n3. a complete change of physical form or substance especially as by magic or witchcraft\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "dictum",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. an authoritative declaration\n2. an opinion voiced by a judge on a point of law not directly bearing on the case in question and therefore not binding\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "synthesis",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the process of producing a chemical compound (usually by the union of simpler chemical compounds\n2. the combination of ideas into a complex whole\n3. reasoning from the general to the particular (or from cause to effect\n"
      },
      "Answer": "b. Apogee (n.) means the highest or farthest point, culmination; thepoint in its orbit where a satellite is at the greatest distance fromthe body it is orbiting."
    },
    "41": {
      "Question": ".41.The ______ townspeople celebrated the soldier\u2019s return to hishome by adorning trees with yellow ribbons and balloons.12",
      "a": {
        "option": "somber",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. lacking brightness or color; dull\n2. grave or even gloomy in character\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "jubilant",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. joyful and proud especially because of triumph or success\n2. full of high-spirited delight\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "pitiless",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. without mercy or pity\n2. deficient in humane and kindly feelings\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "cunning",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. shrewdness as demonstrated by being skilled in deception\n2. crafty artfulness (especially in deception\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. attractive especially by means of smallness or prettiness or quaintness\n2. marked by skill in deception\n3. showing inventiveness and skill\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "unsullied",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. spotlessly clean and fresh\n2. (of reputation\n"
      },
      "Answer": "b. Jubilant (adj.) means rejoicing; expressing joyfulness; exulting."
    },
    "42": {
      "Question": ".42.The governor-elect was hounded by a group of ______ lobbyists",
      "a": {
        "option": "facetious",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. cleverly amusing in tone\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "abstruse",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. difficult to penetrate; incomprehensible to one of ordinary understanding or knowledge\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "magnanimous",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. noble and generous in spirit\n2. generous and understanding and tolerant\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "fawning",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. show submission or fear\n2. try to gain favor by cringing or flattering\n3. have fawns\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. attempting to win favor from influential people by flattery\n2. attempting to win favor by flattery\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "saccharine",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. overly sweet\n"
      },
      "Answer": "d. Fawning (adj.) means attempting to win favor or attention byexcessive \ufb02attery, ingratiating displays of affection, or servilecompliance; obsequious."
    },
    "43": {
      "Question": ".43.The mock graduation ceremony\u2014with a trained skunk posing asthe college president\u2014was a complete ______ that offended many",
      "c": {
        "option": "quintessence",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the fifth and highest element after air and earth and fire and water; was believed to be the substance composing all heavenly bodies\n2. the purest and most concentrated essence of something\n3. the most typical example or representative of a type\n"
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "tempest",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a violent commotion or disturbance\n2. (literary\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "epitome",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a standard or typical example\n2. a brief abstract (as of an article or book\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "travesty",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a comedy characterized by broad satire and improbable situations\n2. a composition that imitates or misrepresents somebody's style, usually in a humorous way\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. make a travesty of\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "recitative",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a vocal passage of narrative text that a singer delivers with natural rhythms of speech\n"
      },
      "Answer": "d. Travesty (n.) means a parody; a grotesque imitation with theintent to ridicule."
    },
    "44": {
      "Question": ".44.The busy, ______ fabric of the clown\u2019s tie matched his oversizedjacket, which was equally atrocious.",
      "a": {
        "option": "mottled",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. mark with spots or blotches of different color or shades of color as if stained\n2. colour with streaks or blotches of different shades\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. having spots or patches of color\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "bleak",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. offering little or no hope\n2. providing no shelter or sustenance\n3. unpleasantly cold and damp\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "credible",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. capable of being believed\n2. (a common but incorrect usage where `credulous' would be appropriate\n3. appearing to merit belief or acceptance\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "malleable",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. easily influenced\n2. capable of being shaped or bent or drawn out\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "communicable",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. (of disease\n2. readily communicated\n"
      },
      "Answer": "a. Mottled (adj.) means blotched or spotted with different colors orshades."
    },
    "45": {
      "Question": ".45.Kendrick\u2019s talent ______ under the tutelage of Anya Kowalonek,who as a young woman had been the most accomplished pianist inher native Lithuania.",
      "a": {
        "option": "bantered",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. be silly or tease one another\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "touted",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. advertize in strongly positive terms\n2. show off\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "\ufb02ourished",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "embellished",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. add details to\n2. be beautiful to look at\n3. make more attractive by adding ornament, colour, etc.\n4. make more beautiful\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "colluded",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. act in unison or agreement and in secret towards a deceitful or illegal purpose\n"
      },
      "Answer": "c. To \ufb02ourish (v.) is (of artists) to be in a state of high productivity,excellence, or in\ufb02uence; to grow luxuriously, thrive; to fare well,prosper, increase in wealth, honor, comfort or whatever isdesirable; to make bold, sweeping movements."
    },
    "46": {
      "Question": ".46.The children were ______ by the seemingly nonsensical clues untilKinan pointed out that the messages were in code.",
      "a": {
        "option": "censured",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. rebuke formally\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "striated",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. mark with striae or striations\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "feigned",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. make believe with the intent to deceive\n2. make a pretence of\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. not genuine\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "prevaricated",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. be deliberately ambiguous or unclear in order to mislead or withhold information\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "\ufb02ummoxed",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. To \ufb02ummox (v.) is to confuse, perplex, bewilder."
    },
    "47": {
      "Question": ".47.As the ______ in Romeo and Juliet, Romeo is a hero able tofor Juliet.",
      "c": {
        "option": "facade",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the face or front of a building\n2. a showy misrepresentation intended to conceal something unpleasant\n"
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "protagonist",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a person who backs a politician or a team etc.\n2. the principal character in a work of fiction\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "enigma",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. something that baffles understanding and cannot be explained\n2. a difficult problem\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "activist",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a militant reformer\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. advocating or engaged in activism\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "catechist",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. one who instructs catechumens in preparation for baptism (especially one using a catechism\n"
      },
      "Answer": "a. A protagonist (n.) is the main character in a drama."
    },
    "48": {
      "Question": ".48.The chess master promised to ______ havoc upon his opponent\u2019spawns for taking his bishop.",
      "a": {
        "option": "wreak",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. cause to happen or to occur as a consequence\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "warrant",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a writ from a court commanding police to perform specified acts\n2. a type of security issued by a corporation (usually together with a bond or preferred stock\n3. formal and explicit approval\n4. a written assurance that some product or service will be provided or will meet certain specifications\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. provide adequate grounds to justify (a certain course of action\n2. stand behind and guarantee the quality, accuracy, or condition of\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "ensue",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. issue or terminate (in a specified way, state, etc.\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "placate",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. cause to be more favorably inclined; gain the good will of\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "endow",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. give qualities or abilities to\n2. furnish with an endowment\n"
      },
      "Answer": "a. To wreak (v.) means to in\ufb02ict, as a revenge or punishment."
    },
    "49": {
      "Question": ".49.I have always admired Seymour\u2019s ______; I\u2019ve never seen himrattled by anything.",
      "a": {
        "option": "aplomb",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. great coolness and composure under strain\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "con\ufb02uence",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "propriety",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. correct or appropriate behavior\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "compunction",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a feeling of deep regret (usually for some misdeed\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "nostalgia",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. longing for something past\n"
      },
      "Answer": "a. Aplomb (n.) is self-assurance, composure, poise, especially understrain."
    },
    "50": {
      "Question": ".50.The soldiers received a military ______ to inspect all their vehicles14",
      "b": {
        "option": "dominion",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. dominance or power through legal authority\n2. a region marked off for administrative or other purposes\n3. one of the self-governing nations in the British Commonwealth\n"
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "allotment",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a share set aside for a specific purpose\n2. the act of distributing by allotting or apportioning; distribution according to a plan\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "affectation",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a deliberate pretense or exaggerated display\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "calculation",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the procedure of calculating; determining something by mathematical or logical methods\n2. problem solving that involves numbers or quantities\n3. planning something carefully and intentionally\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "mandate",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a document giving an official instruction or command\n2. a territory surrendered by Turkey or Germany after World War I and put under the tutelage of some other European power until they are able to stand by themselves\n3. the commission that is given to a government and its policies through an electoral victory\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. assign under a mandate\n2. make mandatory\n3. assign authority to\n"
      },
      "Answer": "e. Mandate (n.) is a command or authoritative instruction.16501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    }
  },
  "Chapter 3": {
    "51": {
      "Question": ".51.As ______ beings we live each day conscious of our shortcomings",
      "a": {
        "option": "sensational",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. causing intense interest, curiosity, or emotion\n2. commanding attention\n3. relating to or concerned in sensation\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "sentient",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. endowed with feeling and unstructured consciousness\n2. consciously perceiving\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "sentimental",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. given to or marked by sentiment or sentimentality\n2. effusively or insincerely emotional\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "static",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a crackling or hissing noise caused by electrical interference\n2. angry criticism\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. not in physical motion\n2. concerned with or producing or caused by static electricity\n3. showing little if any change\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "senile",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. mentally or physically infirm with age\n"
      },
      "Answer": "b. Sentient (adj.) means possessing the power of sense or sense-perception; conscious."
    },
    "52": {
      "Question": ".52.The curious crowd gathered to watch the irate customer ______Chapter 3",
      "a": {
        "option": "antiquate",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. make obsolete or old-fashioned\n2. give an antique appearance to\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "trivialize",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. make trivial or insignificant\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "rant",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a loud bombastic declamation expressed with strong emotion\n2. pompous or pretentious talk or writing\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. talk in a noisy, excited, or declamatory manner\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "placate",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. cause to be more favorably inclined; gain the good will of\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "fetter",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a shackle for the ankles or feet\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. restrain with fetters\n"
      },
      "Answer": "c. To rant (v.) means to speak loudly or violently."
    },
    "53": {
      "Question": ".53.The man\u2019s ______ driving resulted in a four-car pile-up on thefreeway.",
      "a": {
        "option": "burdensome",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. not easily borne; wearing\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "charismatic",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. possessing an extraordinary ability to attract\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "exceptional",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. far beyond what is usual in magnitude or degree\n2. surpassing what is common or usual or expected\n3. deviating widely from a norm of physical or mental ability; used especially of children below normal in intelligence\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "boastful",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. exhibiting self-importance\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "negligent",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. characterized by neglect and undue lack of concern\n"
      },
      "Answer": "e. Negligent (adj.) means to habitually lack in giving proper care orattention; having a careless manner."
    },
    "54": {
      "Question": ".54.Ron didn\u2019t know the rules of rugby, but he could tell by the",
      "c": {
        "option": "juncture",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. an event that occurs at a critical time\n2. a crisis situation or point in time when a critical decision must be made\n3. the shape or manner in which things come together and a connection is made\n"
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "acclamation",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. enthusiastic approval\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "conviction",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. an unshakable belief in something without need for proof or evidence\n2. (criminal law\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "enigma",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. something that baffles understanding and cannot be explained\n2. a difficult problem\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "revelation",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the speech act of making something evident\n2. an enlightening or astonishing disclosure\n3. communication of knowledge to man by a divine or supernatural agency\n4. the last book of the New Testament; contains visionary descriptions of heaven and of conflicts between good and evil and of the end of the world; attributed to Saint John the Apostle\n"
      },
      "Answer": "c. Juncture (n.) is a point of time, especially one that is at a criticalpoint."
    },
    "55": {
      "Question": ".55.My ancestor who lost his life in the Revolutionary War was a______ for American independence.",
      "a": {
        "option": "knave",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a deceitful and unreliable scoundrel\n2. one of four face cards in a deck bearing a picture of a young prince\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "reactionary",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. an extreme conservative; an opponent of progress or liberalism\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. opposed to political or social liberalism or reform\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "compatriot",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a person from your own country\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "nonconformist",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a Protestant in England who is not a member of the Church of England\n2. someone who refuses to conform to established standards of conduct\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. not conforming to some norm or socially approved pattern of behavior or thought\n2. not conforming to established customs or doctrines especially in religion\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "martyr",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. one who suffers for the sake of principle\n2. one who voluntarily suffers death as the penalty for refusing to renounce their religion\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. kill as a martyr\n2. torture and torment like a martyr\n"
      },
      "Answer": "e. A martyr (n.) is one who sacri\ufb01ces something of supreme value,such as a life, for a cause or principle; a victim; one who suffersconstantly."
    },
    "56": {
      "Question": ".56.The ______ sound of the radiator as it released steam became anincreasingly annoying distraction.",
      "a": {
        "option": "sibilant",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a consonant characterized by a hissing sound (like s or sh\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. of speech sounds produced by forcing air through a constricted passage (as `f', `s', `z', or `th' in both `thin' and `then'\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "scintillating",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. give off\n2. reflect brightly\n3. emit or reflect light in a flickering manner\n4. physics: fluoresce momentarily when struck by a charged particle or high-energy photon\n5. be lively or brilliant or exhibit virtuosity\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. brilliantly clever\n2. marked by high spirits or excitement\n3. having brief brilliant points or flashes of light\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "diverting",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. turn aside; turn away from\n2. send on a course or in a direction different from the planned or intended one\n3. occupy in an agreeable, entertaining or pleasant fashion\n4. withdraw (money\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. providing enjoyment; pleasantly entertaining\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "sinuous",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. curved or curving in and out\n2. gracefully thin and bending and moving with ease\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "scurrilous",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. expressing offensive reproach\n"
      },
      "Answer": "a. Sibilant (adj.) means characterized by a hissing sound."
    },
    "57": {
      "Question": ".57.It is helpful for salesmen to develop a good ______ with their18",
      "c": {
        "option": "ire",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a strong emotion; a feeling that is oriented toward some real or supposed grievance\n2. belligerence aroused by a real or supposed wrong (personified as one of the deadly sins\n"
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "platitude",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a trite or obvious remark\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "rapport",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a relationship of mutual understanding or trust and agreement between people\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "tribute",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. something given or done as an expression of esteem\n2. payment by one nation for protection by another\n3. payment extorted by gangsters on threat of violence\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "disinclination",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. that toward which you are inclined to feel dislike\n2. a certain degree of unwillingness\n"
      },
      "Answer": "b. A rapport (n.) is a relationship that is useful and harmonious."
    },
    "58": {
      "Question": ".58.In such a small of\ufb01ce setting, the of\ufb01ce manager found he had______ responsibilities that required knowledge in a variety of",
      "d": {
        "option": "manifold",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a pipe that has several lateral outlets to or from other pipes\n2. a lightweight paper used with carbon paper to make multiple copies\n3. a set of points such as those of a closed surface or an analogue in three or more dimensions\nVerb meaning(s):\n1. make multiple copies of\n2. combine or increase by multiplication\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. many and varied; having many features or forms\n"
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "heedless",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. marked by or paying little heed or attention\n2. characterized by careless unconcern\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "complementary",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. either one of two chromatic colors that when mixed together give white (in the case of lights\n2. in the case of pigments\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. of words or propositions so related that each is the negation of the other\n2. acting as or providing a complement (something that completes the whole\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "mutual",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. common to or shared by two or more parties\n2. concerning each of two or more persons or things; especially given or done in return\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "correlative",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. either of two or more related or complementary variables\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. mutually related\n2. expressing a reciprocal or complementary relation\n"
      },
      "Answer": "d. Manifold (adj.) means many and varied; of many kinds; multiple."
    },
    "59": {
      "Question": ".59.David\u2019s ______ entrance on stage disrupted the scene and causedthe actors to \ufb02ub their lines.",
      "a": {
        "option": "untimely",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. badly timed\n2. uncommonly early or before the expected time\nAdverb meaning(s):\n1. too soon; in a premature manner\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "precise",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. sharply exact or accurate or delimited\n2. (of ideas, images, representations, expressions\n"
      },
      "c": { "option": "lithe", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "fortuitous",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. having no cause or apparent cause\n2. occurring by happy chance\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "tensile",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. of or relating to tension\n2. capable of being shaped or bent or drawn out\n"
      },
      "Answer": "a. Untimely (adj.) means happening before the proper time."
    },
    "60": {
      "Question": ".60.The settlers found an ideal location with plenty of ______ land forfarming and a mountain stream for fresh water and irrigation.",
      "a": {
        "option": "candid",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. characterized by directness in manner or speech; without subtlety or evasion\n2. informal or natural; especially caught off guard or unprepared\n3. openly straightforward and direct without reserve or secretiveness\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "provincial",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. (Roman Catholic Church\n2. a country person\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. of or associated with a province\n2. characteristic of the provinces or their people\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "arable",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. (of farmland\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "timid",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. people who are fearful and cautious\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. showing fear and lack of confidence\n2. lacking self-confidence\n3. lacking conviction or boldness or courage\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "quaint",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. strange in an interesting or pleasing way\n2. very strange or unusual; odd or even incongruous in character or appearance\n3. attractively old-fashioned (but not necessarily authentic\n"
      },
      "Answer": "c. Arable (adj.) means suitable for cultivation, \ufb01t for plowing andfarming productively."
    },
    "61": {
      "Question": ".61.The ______ seventh-grader towered over the other players on his",
      "b": {
        "option": "studious",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. marked by care and effort\n2. characterized by diligent study and fondness for reading\n"
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "gangling",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. tall and thin and having long slender limbs\n2. tall and thin\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "mimetic",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. characterized by or of the nature of or using mimesis\n2. exhibiting mimicry\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "abject",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. of the most contemptible kind\n2. most unfortunate or miserable\n3. showing utter resignation or hopelessness\n4. showing humiliation or submissiveness\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "reserved",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. hold back or set aside, especially for future use or contingency\n2. give or assign a resource to a particular person or cause\n3. obtain or arrange (for oneself\n4. arrange for and reserve (something for someone else\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. set aside for the use of a particular person or party\n2. marked by self-restraint and reticence\n"
      },
      "Answer": "a. Gangling (adj.) means awkward, lanky, or unusually tall and thin."
    },
    "62": {
      "Question": ".62.Carson was at \ufb01rst \ufb02attered by the ______ of his new colleagues,",
      "b": {
        "option": "adulation",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. servile flattery; exaggerated and hypocritical praise\n"
      },
      "c": { "option": "bulwark", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": {
        "option": "reprisal",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a retaliatory action against an enemy in wartime\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "rapport",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a relationship of mutual understanding or trust and agreement between people\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "retinue",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the group following and attending to some important person\n"
      },
      "Answer": "b. Adulation (n.) means strong or excessive admiration or praise;fawning \ufb02attery."
    },
    "63": {
      "Question": ".63.For a(n) ______ fee, it is possible to upgrade from regular gasolineto premium.",
      "a": {
        "option": "nominal",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a phrase that can function as the subject or object of a verb\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. relating to or constituting or bearing or giving a name\n2. insignificantly small; a matter of form only (`tokenish' is informal\n3. pertaining to a noun or to a word group that functions as a noun\n4. of, relating to, or characteristic of an amount that is not adjusted for inflation\n5. named; bearing the name of a specific person\n6. existing in name only\n7. or titular\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "judgmental",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. depending on judgment\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "existential",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. derived from experience or the experience of existence\n2. of or as conceived by existentialism\n3. relating to or dealing with existence (especially with human existence\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "bountiful",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. given or giving freely\n2. producing in abundance\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "jovial",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. full of or showing high-spirited merriment\n"
      },
      "Answer": "a. Nominal (adj.) means small, virtually nothing, or much belowthe actual value of a thing."
    },
    "64": {
      "Question": ".64.Searching frantically to \ufb01nd the hidden jewels, the thievesproceeded to ______ the entire house.",
      "a": {
        "option": "justify",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. show to be right by providing justification or proof\n2. (used of God\n3. adjust the spaces between words\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "darken",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. become dark or darker\n2. tarnish or stain\n3. make dark or darker\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "amplify",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. increase in size, volume or significance\n2. to enlarge beyond bounds or the truth\n3. exaggerate or make bigger\n4. increase the volume of\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "ransack",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. steal goods; take as spoils\n2. search thoroughly\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "glorify",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. praise, glorify, or honor\n2. bestow glory upon\n3. elevate or idealize, in allusion to Christ's transfiguration\n4. cause to seem more splendid\n"
      },
      "Answer": "d. To ransack (v.) means to thoroughly search, to plunder, pillage.24501 Sentence Completion Questions25"
    },
    "65": {
      "Question": ".65.The ______ deer stuck close to its mother when venturing out intothe open \ufb01eld.20",
      "a": {
        "option": "starling",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. gregarious birds native to the Old World\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "foundling",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a child who has been abandoned and whose parents are unknown\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "yearling",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a young child\n2. a racehorse considered one year old until the second Jan. 1 following its birth\n3. an animal in its second year\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "begrudging",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. be envious of; set one's heart on\n2. wish ill or allow unwillingly\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "hatchling",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. any recently hatched animal (especially birds\n"
      },
      "Answer": "c. A yearling (n.) is a young animal past its \ufb01rst year but not yettwo years old."
    },
    "66": {
      "Question": ".66.The police of\ufb01cer ______ the crowd to step back from the \ufb01re sothat no one would get hurt.",
      "a": {
        "option": "undulated",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. stir up (water\n2. occur in soft rounded shapes\n3. move in a wavy pattern or with a rising and falling motion\n4. increase and decrease in volume or pitch, as if in waves\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "enjoined",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. issue an injunction\n2. give instructions to or direct somebody to do something with authority\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "stagnated",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. stand still\n2. cause to stagnate\n3. cease to flow; stand without moving\n4. be idle; exist in a changeless situation\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "permeated",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. spread or diffuse through\n2. pass through\n3. penetrate mutually or be interlocked\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "delineated",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. show the form or outline of\n2. determine the essential quality of\n3. trace the shape of\n4. make a mark or lines on a surface\n5. describe in vivid detail\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. represented accurately or precisely\n"
      },
      "Answer": "b. To enjoin (v.) means to issue an order or command; to direct orimpose with authority."
    },
    "67": {
      "Question": ".67.Jackson\u2019s poor typing skills were a ______ to \ufb01nding employment",
      "a": {
        "option": "bene\ufb01t",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "hindrance",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. something immaterial that interferes with or delays action or progress\n2. any obstruction that impedes or is burdensome\n3. the act of hindering or obstructing or impeding\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "partiality",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a predisposition to like something\n2. an inclination to favor one group or view or opinion over alternatives\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "temptation",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. something that seduces or has the quality to seduce\n2. the desire to have or do something that you know you should avoid\n3. the act of influencing by exciting hope or desire\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "canon",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a rule or especially body of rules or principles generally established as valid and fundamental in a field of art or philosophy\n2. a priest who is a member of a cathedral chapter\n3. a ravine formed by a river in an area with little rainfall\n4. a contrapuntal piece of music in which a melody in one part is imitated exactly in other parts\n5. a complete list of saints that have been recognized by the Roman Catholic Church\n6. a collection of books accepted as holy scripture especially the books of the Bible recognized by any Christian church as genuine and inspired\n"
      },
      "Answer": "b. Hindrance (n.) is an impediment or obstruction; a state of beinghindered; a cause of being prevented or impeded."
    },
    "68": {
      "Question": ".68.Through ______, the chef created a creamy sauce by combiningmedium-high heat.",
      "b": {
        "option": "obscurity",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the quality of being unclear or abstruse and hard to understand\n2. an obscure and unimportant standing; not well known\n3. the state of being indistinct or indefinite for lack of adequate illumination\n"
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "impasse",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a situation in which no progress can be made or no advancement is possible\n2. a street with only one way in or out\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "decadence",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the state of being degenerate in mental or moral qualities\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "diversion",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. an activity that diverts or amuses or stimulates\n2. a turning aside (of your course or attention or concern\n3. an attack calculated to draw enemy defense away from the point of the principal attack\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "liquefaction",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the conversion of a solid or a gas into a liquid\n"
      },
      "Answer": "e. Liquefaction (n.) is the process of liquefying a solid or making aliquid."
    },
    "69": {
      "Question": ".69.The defendant claimed that he was innocent and that his",
      "c": {
        "option": "terse",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. brief and to the point; effectively cut short\n"
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "coerced",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. to cause to do through pressure or necessity, by physical, moral or intellectual means\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "\ufb02agrant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "benign",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. not dangerous to health; not recurrent or progressive (especially of a tumor\n2. pleasant and beneficial in nature or influence\n3. kindness of disposition or manner\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "futile",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. producing no result or effect\n2. unproductive of success\n"
      },
      "Answer": "a. To coerce (v.) is to force to do through pressure, threats, orintimidation; to compel."
    },
    "70": {
      "Question": ".70.Harvey was discouraged that his visa application was ______ due tohis six convictions.",
      "a": {
        "option": "lethargic",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. deficient in alertness or activity\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "immeasurable",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. impossible to measure\n2. beyond calculation or measure\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "nulli\ufb01ed",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "segregated",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. separate by race or religion; practice a policy of racial segregation\n2. divide from the main body or mass and collect\n3. separate or isolate (one thing\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. separated or isolated from others or a main group\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "aggravated",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. make worse\n2. exasperate or irritate\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. made more severe or intense especially in law\n2. incited, especially deliberately, to anger\n"
      },
      "Answer": "c. To nullify (v.) means to make invalid or nonexistent."
    },
    "71": {
      "Question": ".71.The rebel spies were charged with ______ and put on trial.",
      "a": {
        "option": "sedition",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. an illegal action inciting resistance to lawful authority and tending to cause the disruption or overthrow of the government\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "attrition",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. erosion by friction\n2. the wearing down of rock particles by friction due to water or wind or ice\n3. sorrow for sin arising from fear of damnation\n4. a wearing down to weaken or destroy\n5. the act of rubbing together; wearing something down by friction\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "interaction",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a mutual or reciprocal action; interacting\n2. (physics\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "reiteration",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the act of repeating over and again (or an instance thereof\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "perdition",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. (Christianity\n"
      },
      "Answer": "a. Sedition (n.) means resistance, insurrection; conduct directedagainst public order and the tranquility of the state."
    },
    "72": {
      "Question": ".72.Keith was ______ in his giving to friends and charities throughoutthe year, not just during the holidays.",
      "a": {
        "option": "muni\ufb01cent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "portly",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. euphemisms for `fat'\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "amphibious",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. relating to or characteristic of animals of the class Amphibia\n2. operating or living on land and in water\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "guileful",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. marked by skill in deception\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "forensic",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. of, relating to, or used in public debate or argument\n2. used or applied in the investigation and establishment of facts or evidence in a court of law\n"
      },
      "Answer": "a. Muni\ufb01cent (adj.) means extremely generous or liberal in giving;lavish."
    },
    "73": {
      "Question": ".73.Calvin reached the ______ of his career in his early thirties whenhe became president and CEO of a software company.",
      "a": {
        "option": "zephyr",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a slight wind (usually refreshing\n2. (Greek mythology\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "plethora",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. extreme excess\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "vale",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a long depression in the surface of the land that usually contains a river\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "nocturne",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a pensive lyrical piece of music (especially for the piano\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "zenith",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. the point above the observer that is directly opposite the nadir on the imaginary sphere against which celestial bodies appear to be projected\n"
      },
      "Answer": "e. Zenith (n.) means the highest point of any path or course."
    },
    "74": {
      "Question": ".74.Although I\u2019d asked a simple \u201cyes\u201d or \u201cno\u201d question, Irfan\u2019s replywas ______, and I didn\u2019t know how to interpret it.22",
      "a": {
        "option": "prodigal",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a recklessly extravagant consumer\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. recklessly wasteful\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "irate",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. feeling or showing extreme anger\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "equivocal",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. open to two or more interpretations; or of uncertain nature or significance; or (often\n2. or ambiguous\n3. open to question\n4. uncertain as a sign or indication\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "voracious",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. excessively greedy and grasping\n2. devouring or craving food in great quantities\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "harrowing",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. draw a harrow over (land\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. extremely painful\n"
      },
      "Answer": "c. Equivocal (adj.) means open to two or more interpretations,ambiguous and often intended to mislead; open to question,uncertain."
    },
    "75": {
      "Question": ".75.The high-pro\ufb01le company CEO was given an ______ for speaking",
      "a": {
        "option": "expiation",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. compensation for a wrong\n2. the act of atoning for sin or wrongdoing (especially appeasing a deity\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "honorarium",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a fee paid for a nominally free service\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "inoculation",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. taking a vaccine as a precaution against contracting a disease\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "interpretation",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a mental representation of the meaning or significance of something\n2. the act of interpreting something as expressed in an artistic performance\n3. an explanation that results from interpreting something\n4. an explanation of something that is not immediately obvious\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "inquisition",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a former tribunal of the Roman Catholic Church (1232-1820\n2. a severe interrogation (often violating the rights or privacy of individuals\n"
      },
      "Answer": "b. Honorarium (n.) is payment or reward for services for whichpayment is not usually required.501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    }
  },
  "Chapter 4": {
    "76": {
      "Question": ".76.Zachary was doomed to a miserable life, for no matter how muchhe had, he always ______ the possessions of others.",
      "a": {
        "option": "protracted",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. lengthen in time; cause to be or last longer\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. relatively long in duration; tediously protracted\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "exalted",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. praise, glorify, or honor\n2. fill with sublime emotion\n3. heighten or intensify\n4. raise in rank, character, or status\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. of high moral or intellectual value; elevated in nature or style\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "engendered",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. call forth\n2. make (offspring\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "coveted",
        "meaning": "Verb meaning(s):\n1. wish, long, or crave for (something, especially the property of another person\nAdjective meaning(s):\n1. greatly desired\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "\ufb01libustered",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. To covet (v.) is to wish or long for; to feel immoderate desire forthat which belongs to another."
    },
    "77": {
      "Question": ".77.Sheila\u2019s grueling hike included passing through numerous ______.Chapter 4",
      "a": {
        "option": "terrariums",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a vivarium in which selected living plants are kept and observed\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "neoprene",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a synthetic rubber that is resistant to oils and aging; used in waterproof products\n"
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "jurisdictions",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. in law; the territory within which power can be exercised\n"
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "ravines",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a deep narrow steep-sided valley (especially one formed by running water\n"
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "belfries",
        "meaning": "Noun meaning(s):\n1. a bell tower; usually stands alone unattached to a building\n2. a room (often at the top of a tower\n"
      },
      "Answer": "d. A ravine (n.) is a deep narrow canyon."
    },
    "78": {
      "Question": ".78.The college professor was known on campus as a ______",
      "c": {
        "option": "auspicious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "staid",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. characterized by dignity and propriety\n"
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "stagnant",
        "meaning": "Adjective meaning(s):\n1. not circulating or flowing\n2. not growing or changing; without force or vitality\n"
      },
      "d": { "option": "sterile", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "dogmatic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Staid (adj.) means of a steady and sober character; prudentlyreserved and colorless."
    },
    "79": {
      "Question": ".79.Because he was so ______, the athlete was able to complete theobstacle course in record time.",
      "a": {
        "option": "belligerent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "nimble", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "demure", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "volatile",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "speculative",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Nimble (adj.) is quick and light in movement, to be agile."
    },
    "80": {
      "Question": ".80.The toy store\u2019s extensive inventory offered a ______ of toys from",
      "b": { "option": "lexicon", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": {
        "option": "manifold",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "burrow", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "gamut", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "motif", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "d. A gamut (n.) is an entire range or a whole series."
    },
    "81": {
      "Question": ".81.With sunscreen and a good book, April ______ by the pool in herlounge chair while the children swam.28",
      "a": {
        "option": "ensconced",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "sustained",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "expelled",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "transcended",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "lolled", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "e. To loll (v.) is to lean, recline, or act lazily or indolently; lounge."
    },
    "82": {
      "Question": ".82.NaQuan had a terrible habit of boasting so much about hissmallest accomplishments that his ______ became renownedthroughout the small college campus.",
      "a": {
        "option": "vainglory",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "timidity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "dif\ufb01dence",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "tempestuousness",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "mockery", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "a. Vainglory (n.) means excessive, pretentious, and demonstrativevanity."
    },
    "83": {
      "Question": ".83.Only a small number of people in the audience laughed at thesarcastic.",
      "c": {
        "option": "venturous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "consequential",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "avaricious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "dauntless",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "mordant", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "e. Mordant (adj.) means bitingly sarcastic or harshly caustic."
    },
    "84": {
      "Question": ".84.He has long been a(n) ______ of year-round school, believing itwould signi\ufb01cantly improve learning and ease the burden onworking parents.",
      "a": {
        "option": "advocate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "levity", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "detractor",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "epiphany",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "connoisseur",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. An advocate (n.) is one who argues for a cause, a supporter ordefender; one who pleads on another\u2019s behalf."
    },
    "85": {
      "Question": ".85.Tired of hearing the child whine for more candy, the babysitter\ufb01nally ______ and offered him a piece of chocolate.",
      "a": {
        "option": "relented",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "abated", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "rendered",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "placated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "enumerated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. To relent (v.) means to yield or comply."
    },
    "86": {
      "Question": ".86.Dogs growl and show their teeth in an attempt to ______ the",
      "a": { "option": "bolster", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "waylay", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "cow", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "exacerbate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "appease", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "c. To cow (v.) is to intimidate, frighten with threats or show offorce."
    },
    "87": {
      "Question": ".87.In biology class, Sabine observed the slug\u2019s ______, its barely",
      "d": { "option": "insight", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": { "option": "parody", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "prescience",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "torpor", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "vigor", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "c. Torpor (n.) means extreme sluggishness; lethargy or apathy;dullness."
    },
    "88": {
      "Question": ".88.The ______ instinct of a watchdog is to attack strangers who enterits home.",
      "a": {
        "option": "judicious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "intimate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "pragmatic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "melancholy",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "primal", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "e. Primal (adj.) means primary, the \ufb01rst in order or the original;primitive."
    },
    "89": {
      "Question": ".89.The battalion\u2019s ______ was a well-forti\ufb01ed structure near the",
      "e": {
        "option": "garrison",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "labyrinth",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "summary", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "villa", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "vinculum",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. A garrison (n.) is a fort or outpost where troops are stationed;any military post.34501 Sentence Completion Questions35"
    },
    "90": {
      "Question": ".90.Much to my surprise, my teenage daughter was ______ to the ideaof going out with me on Friday night instead of with her friends.30",
      "a": {
        "option": "contrite",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "impartial",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "partisan",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "deferential",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "amenable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. Amenable (adj.) means disposed or willing to comply; responsive,willing; responsible to a higher authority, accountable."
    },
    "91": {
      "Question": ".91.The enormous waves forced the lobster boat to ______ heavily tothe starboard side, causing crates of lobsters to topple and fall intothe ocean.",
      "a": {
        "option": "tri\ufb02e",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "degenerate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "list", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "expedite",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "disseminate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. To list (v.) (related to a vessel) is to incline or to cause to lean toone side."
    },
    "92": {
      "Question": ".92.Walking through the ______ forest in spring was a welcome escapefrom the cold, gray winter we had spent in the city.",
      "a": { "option": "pliant", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "verdant", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "factious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "bland", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "innocuous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Verdant (adj.) means green with vegetation."
    },
    "93": {
      "Question": ".93.Nina called the humane society when she saw her neighbor ______his dog.",
      "a": { "option": "mandate", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "forebode",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "maltreat",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "stipulate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "peruse", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "c. To maltreat (v.) means to treat poorly; abuse."
    },
    "94": {
      "Question": ".94.Meredith used the ______ to steer the horse and keep him in line.",
      "a": { "option": "jolt", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "bristle", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "chine", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "quirt", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "hearth", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "d. A quirt (n.) is a riding whip with a short handle and braidedrawhide leash."
    },
    "95": {
      "Question": ".95.Oliver was unable to ______ himself from the dif\ufb01culties he had",
      "c": { "option": "oust", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": { "option": "reprove", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "pique", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "extricate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "broach", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "d. To extricate (v.) is to release from an entanglement or dif\ufb01culty,disengage."
    },
    "96": {
      "Question": ".96.The ______ of our expedition was still so far away that I felt wewould never get there.",
      "a": { "option": "nadir", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "terminus",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "speculation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "apex", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "dungeon", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "b. The terminus (n) is the \ufb01nal point or goal; the \ufb01nal stop on atransportation line."
    },
    "97": {
      "Question": ".97.If he expected to ______ as a doctor, Lou knew he would have tostudy hard in medical school and work long hours to gain",
      "e": { "option": "mediate", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": {
        "option": "perpetrate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "palliate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "palpitate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "prosper", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "d. To prosper (v.) means to be successful."
    },
    "98": {
      "Question": ".98.Doc Wilson grew up in Florida and was not prepared to face the______ climate of the Alaskan winter.",
      "a": {
        "option": "freshwater",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "gelid", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "compendious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "subsidiary",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "improvident",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Gelid (adj.) means icy or extremely cold; possessing a cold orunfriendly manner."
    },
    "99": {
      "Question": ".99.Marvin\u2019s ______ prevented him from \ufb01nishing his work and was32",
      "e": {
        "option": "rescission",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "loquacity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "heroism", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "decadence",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "depreciation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Loquacity (n.) is talkativeness; the state of continual talking."
    },
    "100": {
      "Question": "0.100.The graph clearly showed the company reaching the ______ inpro\ufb01ts during the 1980s when the economy was in a boom period.",
      "a": { "option": "narthex", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "gullet", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "gamut", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "quiescence",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "vertex", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "e. Vertex (n.) means the highest point of anything; the apex orsummit.501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    }
  },
  "Chapter 5": {
    "101": {
      "Question": "1.101.Amie agrees with the ______ that the grass is always greener onthe other side of the fence.",
      "a": {
        "option": "perpetuity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "penchant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "maxim", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "conformation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "fortitude",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. Maxim (n.) is an established principle or a general truth, often acondensed version of a practical truth."
    },
    "102": {
      "Question": "2.102.Victor Frankenstein\u2019s creature was a(n) ______, detested byChapter 5",
      "e": { "option": "anomaly", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": {
        "option": "itinerant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "anathema",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "cosmopolitan",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "mercenary",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. An anathema (n.) is one who is detested or shunned; one who iscursed or damned; a curse or vehement denunciation; a formalban, curse, or excommunication."
    },
    "103": {
      "Question": "3. Jack Nicholson was at the ______ of his career when he received103. Jack Nicholson was at the ______ of his career when he receivedthe Oscar for Best Actor.",
      "a": {
        "option": "detriment",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "pinnacle",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "oligarchy",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "rogue", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "repose", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "b. A pinnacle (n.) is the highest level or degree available."
    },
    "104": {
      "Question": "4.104.Ariana was outstanding as the moderator; she handled theintensely heated debate with great ______, diplomatically andtactfully keeping the conversation fair and on track.",
      "a": {
        "option": "\ufb01nesse",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "pretentiousness",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "prowess", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "succor", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "aversion",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Finesse (n.) is the subtle, skillful handling of a situation,diplomacy, tact; re\ufb01ned or delicate performance or execution."
    },
    "105": {
      "Question": "5.105.The class endured a loud and lengthy ______ by the teacher on thesubject of submitting written work on time.",
      "a": { "option": "guile", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "polemic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "bravado", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "tirade", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "heresy", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "d. A tirade (n.) is a long and blusterous speech given especiallywhen the speaker is denouncing someone or something."
    },
    "106": {
      "Question": "6.106.Lauren\u2019s ______ features, what you \ufb01rst noticed about her, wereher stunning black hair and large, dark eyes.38",
      "a": { "option": "savvy", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "af\ufb02uent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "predominant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "universal",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "malicious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. Predominant (adj.) means most dominant, common, or frequent;to have surpassing power, in\ufb02uence, or authority."
    },
    "107": {
      "Question": "7. Whenever Tom and I would argue he would ______ with his hands107. Whenever Tom and I would argue he would ______ with his hands",
      "a": {
        "option": "interject",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "infuse", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "gesticulate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "conjure", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "encumber",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. To gesticulate (v.) means to use gestures or make motions;express through motion, especially while speaking."
    },
    "108": {
      "Question": "8.108.Must we be subjected to your ______ complaints all day long?",
      "a": {
        "option": "tiresome",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "fearsome",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "awesome", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "gleesome",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "wholesome",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Tiresome (adj.) means causing to be weary."
    },
    "109": {
      "Question": "9.109.The new political candidate refused to print ______ about her",
      "a": {
        "option": "dispensation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "assignation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "rendition",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "libel", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "compunction",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Libel (n.) is defamatory writing; misrepresentative publication(writing, pictures, signs) that damages a person\u2019s reputation."
    },
    "110": {
      "Question": "0.110.Awkwardly tall and prone to tripping over her own feet, Grace felther name was truly a ______.",
      "a": {
        "option": "misnomer",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "preoccupation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "universality",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "garrulity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "benevolence",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Misnomer (n.) is a misnaming of a person or place; a wrong orunsuitable name."
    },
    "111": {
      "Question": "1. Although the villagers\u2019 lives were profoundly different from her111. Although the villagers\u2019 lives were profoundly different from herown, Jing-Mae felt a deep ______ for the people when she servedin the Peace Corps.",
      "a": {
        "option": "reparation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "af\ufb01nity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "injunction",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "exigency",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "analogy", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "b. An af\ufb01nity (n.) is a natural attraction or liking; a feeling ofkinship, connection or closeness, similarity; relationship bymarriage."
    },
    "112": {
      "Question": "2.112.Sometimes late at night Sharon would gaze joyfully at her children",
      "a": { "option": "sneer", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "ostracize",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "revel", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "repudiate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "antiquate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. To revel (v.) is to take great pleasure or delight."
    },
    "113": {
      "Question": "3.113.In the famous balcony scene, Romeo ______ Juliet\u2019s beauty in oneof the most romantic soliloquies ever written.",
      "a": {
        "option": "sanctions",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "extols", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "peruses", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "beguiles",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "fetters", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "b. To extol (v.) means to praise highly, exalt, glorify.44501 Sentence Completion Questions45"
    },
    "114": {
      "Question": "4.114.It was ______ to think that it could possibly snow in the middle ofthe desert.40",
      "a": {
        "option": "advantageous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "philosophical",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "eroding", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "preventative",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "preposterous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. Preposterous (adj.) means contrary to common sense or utterlyabsurd."
    },
    "115": {
      "Question": "5.115.Every evening at the restaurant, the reporter would eavesdrop onthe Mayor\u2019s conversations in order to ______ any information that",
      "c": { "option": "extol", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": { "option": "ignore", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "glean", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "extend", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "narrate", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "b. To glean (v.) means to gather or collect slowly; to learn ordiscover bit by bit."
    },
    "116": {
      "Question": "6.116.The surgeon placed a ______ on the femoral artery to bind it",
      "d": {
        "option": "synopsis",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "ligature",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "doctrine",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "premise", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "degeneration",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. A ligature (n.) is something that ties or binds up, such as abandage, wire, or cord."
    },
    "117": {
      "Question": "7.117.By sheer ______ force, the men pushed the truck to the side of theroad and out of danger.",
      "a": { "option": "virile", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "persnickety",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "meticulous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "suave", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "contentious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Virile (adj.) means having masculine strength; vigorous orenergetic."
    },
    "118": {
      "Question": "8.118.Based on his recent poor decisions, it was obvious that Seth lacked",
      "e": { "option": "modicum", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": {
        "option": "debasement",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "diversion",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "disapprobation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "submission",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. Modicum (n.) is a small or token amount."
    },
    "119": {
      "Question": "9.119.To settle the dispute, the students elected a faculty member toserve as a(n) ______.",
      "a": {
        "option": "maverick",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "dystopia",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "arbiter", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "\ufb01duciary",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "martyr", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "c. An arbiter (n.) is one selected or appointed to judge or decide adisputed issue, an arbitrator; someone with the power to settlematters at will."
    },
    "120": {
      "Question": "0.120.The ______ newspaper accounts of the city scandal caused somereaders to question the truth of the stories.",
      "a": { "option": "lurid", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "vivacious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "blithesome",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "proli\ufb01c",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "amicable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Lurid (adj.) means glaringly sensational or vivid; shocking."
    },
    "121": {
      "Question": "1.121.The ______ man with amnesia was unable to recognize where he was.",
      "a": {
        "option": "endogenous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "euphoric",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "nonplussed",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "amicable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "pliable", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "c. Nonplussed (adj.) means greatly perplexed, \ufb01lled withbewilderment."
    },
    "122": {
      "Question": "2.122.Justin\u2019s ______ solution to the problem revealed that he did notspend much time considering the consequences.",
      "a": { "option": "facile", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "obsolete",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "resilient",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "pristine",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "ardent", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "a. Facile (adj.) means arrived at or achieved with little dif\ufb01culty oreffort, thus lacking depth, super\ufb01cial; performing or speakingeffectively with effortless ease and \ufb02uency, adroit, eloquent."
    },
    "123": {
      "Question": "3.123.The events of the evening ______ without dif\ufb01culty despite thelack of planning on the part of the host.42",
      "a": { "option": "expired", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "transpired",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "retired", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "ensured", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "extorted",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. To transpire (v.) means to come to pass, to occur."
    },
    "124": {
      "Question": "4.124.It is every American person\u2019s ______ to live the life he or she",
      "c": {
        "option": "prerogative",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "composite",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "eloquence",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "allusion",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "demise", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "c. Prerogative (n.) means an exclusive or special right or privilege."
    },
    "125": {
      "Question": "5.125.After the boisterous customers left the caf\u00e9 without tipping, Carlos______ at them through the restaurant\u2019s front window.",
      "a": {
        "option": "interjected",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "jostled", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "glowered",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "emulated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "skulked", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "c. To glower (v.) means to stare angrily or sullenly, to look intentlywith anger or dislike.501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    }
  },
  "Chapter 6": {
    "126": {
      "Question": "6.126.People often referred to Noelle as ______ because she trusted",
      "e": { "option": "elated", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": {
        "option": "na\u00efve",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "elevated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "boastful",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "panoramic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Na\u00efve (adj.) means lacking worldly experience; possessing achildlike innocence or simplicity."
    },
    "127": {
      "Question": "7.127.Kinnel\u2019s re-election is being threatened by a growing ______ ofChapter 6",
      "d": { "option": "guise", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": { "option": "rogue", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "faction", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "pariah", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "anathema",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. A faction (n.) is a group or clique within a larger group, usually aminority, acting in unison in opposition to the larger group;internal dissension, con\ufb02ict within an organization, nation, orother group."
    },
    "128": {
      "Question": "8.128.The peasants passed their weary days in much ______ and little",
      "c": { "option": "travail", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": {
        "option": "pertinence",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "renown", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "exile", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "repose", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "c. Travail (n.) means hard or agonizing labor."
    },
    "129": {
      "Question": "9.129.Lyasia is a ______ of the clarinet; she has performed solos withmany orchestras and bands around the world.",
      "a": {
        "option": "neophyte",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "novice", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "virtuoso",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "termagant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "plethora",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. Virtuoso (n.) means a master in the technique of some particular\ufb01ne art."
    },
    "130": {
      "Question": "0.130.The children knew that once their father made his decision, thenew rule would be ______ because he would never change his mind.",
      "a": {
        "option": "irrevocable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "articulate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "premeditated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "serried", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "discourteous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Irrevocable (adj.) means irreversible; not able to be revoked orrecalled."
    },
    "131": {
      "Question": "1.131.The haunted house displayed ______ scenes in every room,",
      "c": { "option": "macabre", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": {
        "option": "preparatory",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "archaic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "precocious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "impetuous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. Macabre (adj.) means ghastly, horrible, or gruesome."
    },
    "132": {
      "Question": "2.132.The concert audience was frustrated by the poor ______ of thesounds coming from the speakers.48",
      "a": {
        "option": "modulation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "recrimination",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "terminus",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "dissidence",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "assertion",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Modulation (n.) a regulation by or adjustment to a certainmeasure, such as in music or radio waves."
    },
    "133": {
      "Question": "3.133.Please don\u2019t ______ me my success\u2014I\u2019ve worked hard to earn thispromotion!",
      "a": { "option": "renege", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "begrudge",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "excise", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "staunch", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "vaunt", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "b. To begrudge (v.) means to envy the possession or enjoyment of;to give or allow with reluctance."
    },
    "134": {
      "Question": "4.134.With an ______ blow of the whistle, the meddling parentinterrupted the game to reiterate the rules of the tournament.",
      "a": {
        "option": "industrious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "illustrious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "eloquent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "of\ufb01cious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "enviable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Of\ufb01cious (adj.) means marked by excessive eagerness in offeringunwanted services or advice to others; unof\ufb01cial."
    },
    "135": {
      "Question": "5.135.The candidate\u2019s inappropriately sexist remark was met with a______ of denunciations from the angry crowd.",
      "a": { "option": "bastion", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "fusillade",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "m\u00e9lange",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "dichotomy",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "solecism",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. A fusillade (n.) is a barrage; a rapid discharge of \ufb01rearms,simultaneously or in rapid succession."
    },
    "136": {
      "Question": "6.136.The ______ employee decided to complain publicly about theunacceptable working conditions.",
      "a": {
        "option": "discreet",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "prudent", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "precarious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "malcontent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "stupendous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Malcontent (adj.) means dissatis\ufb01ed, uneasy or discontent; arebel."
    },
    "137": {
      "Question": "7.137.The medicine man applied a sweet smelling ______ to the young",
      "b": {
        "option": "corrosive",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": { "option": "triad", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "parcel", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "unguent", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "pungent", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "d. An unguent (n.) is any soothing or healing ointment or lubricantfor local application.501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    },
    "138": {
      "Question": "8.138.The judge dismissed the extraneous evidence because it was not______ to the trial.",
      "a": {
        "option": "pertinent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "pretentious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "synonymous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "abject", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "inalienable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Pertinent (adj.) means applicable, related to the subject matter athand."
    },
    "139": {
      "Question": "9.139.The ______ nature of the song is supposed to be reminiscent ofshepherds calling to their \ufb02ocks at night.",
      "a": {
        "option": "vocative",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "endemic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "surreptitious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "preternatural",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "inane", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "a. Vocative (adj.) means pertaining to the act of calling."
    },
    "140": {
      "Question": "0.140.The ______ child caused great dif\ufb01culties for her parents andteachers because she refused to correct her bad behavior even inthe face of punishment.",
      "a": {
        "option": "adorable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "sincere", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "incorrigible",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "lamentable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "demure", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "c. Incorrigible (adj.) means bad to the point of being beyondcorrection; uncontrollable; impervious to change."
    },
    "141": {
      "Question": "1.141.The internist decided to treat the ______ with medication, but alsorecommended rest and proper nutrition.50",
      "a": { "option": "malady", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "nonentity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "missive", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "repository",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "nonchalance",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Malady (n.) is a disease or disorder."
    },
    "142": {
      "Question": "2.142.It was such a beautiful day that I decided to go for a ______ on my",
      "b": { "option": "jaunt", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": {
        "option": "expedition",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "pilgrimage",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "repast", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "intimation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. A jaunt (n.) is usually a short journey taken for pleasure."
    },
    "143": {
      "Question": "3.143.The castaway\u2019s hut was ______ by the natives curious to see whothe intruder was upon their island.",
      "a": { "option": "beset", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "surmised",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "precluded",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "garnered",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "lauded", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "a. To beset (v.) means to surround on all sides; to annoy or harasspersistently; to decorate with jewels."
    },
    "144": {
      "Question": "4.144.Sometimes my grandmother would ______ all different types ofthread so she could include more colors in the clothes she sewed.",
      "a": { "option": "daunt", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "raddle", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "scrabble",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "thrush", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "empower", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "b. To raddle (v.) means to twist together, to intertwine."
    },
    "145": {
      "Question": "5.145.The defense attorney\u2019s choice of words ______ that there wereother possible versions of the crime, but the jury was unconvinced.",
      "a": {
        "option": "pervaded",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "insinuated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "discounted",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "imposed", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "ensconced",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. To insinuate (v.) is to hint or suggest; to intimate."
    },
    "146": {
      "Question": "6.146.Ted\u2019s enthusiasm for becoming a professional drum player ______when he realized he would have to practice several hours a day.",
      "a": { "option": "waxed", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "waned", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "deranged",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "\ufb02outed",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "preempted",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. To wane (v.) means to diminish in intensity or size."
    },
    "147": {
      "Question": "7.147.Some would say Muzak is a(n) ______ form of music, a kind of",
      "b": {
        "option": "degenerate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": { "option": "arable", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "volatile",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "pivotal", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "exemplary",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Degenerate (adj.) means having declined in quality or value,reduced from a former or original state, to degrade."
    },
    "148": {
      "Question": "8.148.The teacher was dismissed for the ______ act of helping hisstudents cheat on the exam.",
      "a": {
        "option": "steadfast",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "meritorious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "unconscionable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "pristine",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "fortuitous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. Unconscionable (adj.) means not restrained by conscience;unscrupulous."
    },
    "149": {
      "Question": "9.149.The reformed criminal could not forget his guilty past; he was in aliving state of ______.",
      "a": {
        "option": "perdition",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "tact", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "composure",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "principle",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "veracity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Perdition (n.) the most modern use of the word means eternaldamnation, or a hell."
    },
    "150": {
      "Question": "0.150.The ______ yoga instructor waited patiently for her students to\ufb01nd the proper pose, which she performed with ease.52",
      "a": {
        "option": "unabashed",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "lissome", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "cosmopolitan",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "sneering",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "disparaging",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Lissome (adj.) means lithe or lithesome, usually related to thebody; moving or bending easily or limber.54501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    }
  },
  "Chapter 7": {
    "151": {
      "Question": "1.151.When we \ufb01rst meet Romeo, he is ______ over his unrequited lovefor Rosaline.",
      "a": {
        "option": "brooding",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "ogling", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "meandering",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "embellishing",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "groveling",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. To brood (v.) is to be in deep thought, to think moodily oranxiously about something; to cover over, as with wings, inorder to protect; to hang over, as of something threatening,dark, or menacing, to loom; to be silent or sullen, sulk; to sit onor hatch eggs."
    },
    "152": {
      "Question": "2.152.Because it had been worn and washed so often, Linus\u2019s favorite t-shirt was tattered and ______ with holes.Chapter 7",
      "a": {
        "option": "salvaged",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "circulated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "riddled", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "emulated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "congregated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. To riddle (v.) means to pierce with many holes."
    },
    "153": {
      "Question": "3.153.Henley\u2019s ______ remarks about my presentation did not bother me",
      "b": {
        "option": "voracious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "derogatory",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "tactile", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "capricious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "amiable", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "a. Derogatory (adj.) means tending to lessen in value, to detract ordiminish; disparaging, belittling, injurious."
    },
    "154": {
      "Question": "4.154.Eels swim using a rapid ______ motion that propels them throughthe water.",
      "a": {
        "option": "dissipating",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "undulating",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "eradicating",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "objurgating",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "irritating",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Undulating (adj.) means characterized by a wavelike motion."
    },
    "155": {
      "Question": "5.155.Sick and tired of her boring job, Cecilia began to ______ what itwould be like to quit.",
      "a": { "option": "ponder", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "disengage",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "negate", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "relinquish",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "alleviate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. To ponder (v.) is to weigh carefully in the mind."
    },
    "156": {
      "Question": "6.156.The way my father likes to ______with any salesperson to see if he",
      "c": {
        "option": "capitulate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": { "option": "striate", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "variegate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "teem", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "wrangle", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "e. To wrangle (v.) means to bicker, dispute, create a noisyargument."
    },
    "157": {
      "Question": "7.157.The ______ construction crew built large new buildings all over theEast Coast, wherever the demand for quali\ufb01ed workers took them.56",
      "a": { "option": "laconic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "irresolute",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "itinerant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "parietal",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "peremptory",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. Itinerant (adj.) means traveling from one place to another,usually on a planned course; working in one place for a shortwhile before moving onto another place to work; wandering."
    },
    "158": {
      "Question": "8.158.The CEO\u2019s large expense accounts proved she was a ______spender with the company\u2019s money.",
      "a": {
        "option": "injurious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "ineffectual",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "liberal", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "malignant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "insolvent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. Liberal (adj.) means characterized by generosity or a willingnessto give freely in large amounts; untraditional or broad-mindedin beliefs."
    },
    "159": {
      "Question": "9.159.Daniela found the unchanging rhythm of the musical piece to be",
      "a": {
        "option": "recusant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "monotonous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "irreverent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "coherent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "redolent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Monotonous (adj.) means tediously lacking in variety; unvarying;repetitious."
    },
    "160": {
      "Question": "0.160.The young, thin boy surprised his wrestling opponent with his______ strength.",
      "a": {
        "option": "fraudulent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "wiry", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "frolicsome",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "pretentious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "endemic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "b. Wiry (adj.) means thin, but tough and sinewy."
    },
    "161": {
      "Question": "1.161.The new actress\u2019s talents were severely ______ by the local critics;she went on to be a distinguished member of a well-respected",
      "a": {
        "option": "underrated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "berated", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "placated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "dissuaded",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "interred",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Underrated (adj.) means undervalued."
    },
    "162": {
      "Question": "2.162.To hide his insecurity, Barton often acted like a ______ so that he",
      "c": {
        "option": "neophyte",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": { "option": "buffoon", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "martyr", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "plebian", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "wraith", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "a. A buffoon (n.) is a ludicrous or bumbling person, a fool; someonegiven to clowning and amusing others through ridiculousbehavior; a clown or jester.62501 Sentence Completion Questions63"
    },
    "163": {
      "Question": "3.163.When Arnold\u2019s grandmother began to complain about the______ specialist for a diagnosis.",
      "e": {
        "option": "psychological",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": { "option": "optical", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "oral", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "archeological",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "osteopathic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Osteopathic (adj.) means a system of medicine pertaining to thebone and skeletal system."
    },
    "164": {
      "Question": "4.164.Charlie\u2019s ______ behavior made it clear that he had been highly",
      "e": { "option": "irksome", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": {
        "option": "decorous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "surreptitious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "erratic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "caustic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "a. Decorous (adj.) means characterized by good taste in mannersand conduct, exhibiting propriety or decorum, proper."
    },
    "165": {
      "Question": "5.165.Staring at the ______ crystal blue water of the sea, Eileen thoughtshe had never seen anything so beautiful.58",
      "a": {
        "option": "\ufb02amboyant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "appalling",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "devious", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "pristine",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "\ufb01ery",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Pristine (adj.) means pure, fresh and clean, as if new; original orprimitive."
    },
    "166": {
      "Question": "6.166.Wearing the designer\u2019s latest fashions, the ______ clothing modelsashayed down the runway.",
      "a": { "option": "jaunty", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "tranquil",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "fanatical",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "recessive",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "contemplative",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Jaunty (adj.) means sprightly in manner; stylish or smart indress."
    },
    "167": {
      "Question": "7.167.Given his ______ nature, it was appropriate that he decided to be atrial lawyer after law school.",
      "a": {
        "option": "lackluster",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "engrossed",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "penitent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "litigious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "obsolete",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Litigious (adj.) means inclined to disagree or dispute, especiallyin lawsuits; argumentative."
    },
    "168": {
      "Question": "8.168.After her relationship ended, Patty, feeling ______, insisted onplaying sad love songs repeatedly.",
      "a": {
        "option": "infallible",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "plausible",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "formative",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "mawkish", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "persuasive",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Mawkish (adj.) means characterized by excessive sentimentality;overly emotional."
    },
    "169": {
      "Question": "9.169.Sanji went abroad as a ______ young man; when he returned twoyears later, he seemed like an experienced man of the world.",
      "a": {
        "option": "sardonic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "egalitarian",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "reticent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "callow", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "loquacious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Callow (adj.) means lacking maturity or experience; immature,na\u00efve."
    },
    "170": {
      "Question": "0.170.Normally distinguished and reserved, Robert would act ______when he joined his friends to cheer for their old high school team",
      "a": {
        "option": "indignant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "oa\ufb01sh",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "poignant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "reputable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "obdurate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Oa\ufb01sh (adj.) means acting stupid, goofy, or clumsy."
    },
    "171": {
      "Question": "1.171.The protesters were concerned that the proposed legislation wouldhave a(n) ______ effect on the state\u2019s nature preserves.",
      "a": {
        "option": "scintillating",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "deleterious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "insipid", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "punctilious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "parsimonious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Deleterious (adj.) means having a harmful or adverse effect;destructive, hurtful, noxious."
    },
    "172": {
      "Question": "2.172.Not swayed by his student\u2019s ______ \ufb02attery, the professor told himthat his grade would not be changed.",
      "a": { "option": "forlorn", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "striated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "undulating",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "unctuous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "frowsy", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "d. Unctuous (adj.) means characterized by insincere earnestness;oily or fatty in appearance."
    },
    "173": {
      "Question": "3.173.Tonya found Isaac\u2019s public declarations of his love for her ______60",
      "a": {
        "option": "necrotic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "intriguing",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "witless", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "malodorous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "pliant", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "c. Witless (adj.) means foolish, indiscreet, or silly."
    },
    "174": {
      "Question": "4.174.The young kitten had a ______ look on its face when it noticed themenacing dog entering the yard.",
      "a": { "option": "servile", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "diligent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "scornful",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "pavid", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "optimistic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Pavid (adj.) means timid or fearful."
    },
    "175": {
      "Question": "5.175.According to pirate lore, a terrible ______ would follow whoeveropened the treasure chest.",
      "a": {
        "option": "precursor",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "precession",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "rendition",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "insurgence",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "malediction",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. Malediction (n.) is a curse or a proclaiming of a curse againstsomeone; an imprecation.501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    }
  },
  "Chapter 8": {
    "176": {
      "Question": "6.176.A(n) ______ spirit only causes more stress and strife; it is better toforgive and forget.",
      "a": {
        "option": "apathetic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "restorative",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "\ufb02accid",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "vindictive",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "fortuitous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Vindictive (adj.) means revengeful, hateful."
    },
    "177": {
      "Question": "7.177.When we were renovating the old house, we found a(n) ______ of$10 and $20 bills hidden inside the old laundry chute.Chapter 8",
      "a": { "option": "odyssey", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "matrix", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "lament", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "fodder", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "cache", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "e. A cache (n.) is a hiding place for storing or concealing provisionsor valuables; a secret store of valuables or money, a stash."
    },
    "178": {
      "Question": "8.178.Even though the pilot promised it was safe, Neil was ______ to \ufb02y",
      "d": {
        "option": "reluctant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "habitual",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "overzealous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "pavid", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "salacious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Reluctant (adj.) means unwilling to do what one is being calledto do."
    },
    "179": {
      "Question": "9.179.Ron has few friends because he is ______ and cares only abouthimself.",
      "a": { "option": "mundane", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "intrepid",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "garrulous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "voracious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "egocentric",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. Egocentric (adj.) means caring only about or interested only inoneself or one\u2019s needs."
    },
    "180": {
      "Question": "0.180.The workers attempted to ______ the supervisor\u2019s authority bynegotiating terms with the clients themselves.",
      "a": {
        "option": "contradict",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "instigate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "resonate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "placate", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "undermine",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. To undermine (v.) means to subvert in an underhanded way."
    },
    "181": {
      "Question": "1.181.The student failed his research paper because he chose to ______material from a another author\u2019s work.",
      "a": {
        "option": "authorize",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "stimulate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "overrule",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "plagiarize",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "meditate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. To plagiarize (v.) is to steal thoughts or words in literarycomposition."
    },
    "182": {
      "Question": "2.182.The ______ old cowboy had a complexion that spoke of manyyears in the desert sun, rounding up wild horses.66",
      "a": { "option": "secular", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "suave", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "turgid", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "wizened", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "truant", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "d. Wizened (adj.) means withered or dry, especially with age."
    },
    "183": {
      "Question": "3.183.The swimmer\u2019s back injury ______ his prospects for a gold medal",
      "a": {
        "option": "compelled",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "advanced",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "jeopardized",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "maintained",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "expounded",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. Jeopardize (v.) means to put in jeopardy or at risk; a hazard ordanger."
    },
    "184": {
      "Question": "4.184.As Ramiro strolled through his old neighborhood, he noticedsounds and smells that were ______ of his childhood.",
      "a": {
        "option": "belligerent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "malleable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "reminiscent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "recondite",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "incessant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. Reminiscent (adj.) means calling to mind or remembering."
    },
    "185": {
      "Question": "5.185.Lynette had to learn the ______ of the insurance profession beforeshe felt comfortable describing products to her clients.",
      "a": { "option": "lexicon", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "classicism",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "juncture",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "cessation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "asperity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Lexicon (n.) is the vocabulary used in a language, profession,class, or subject."
    },
    "186": {
      "Question": "6.186.Marta had to pay off her ______ to the credit card company beforeshe could get a mortgage.",
      "a": { "option": "stipend", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "liability",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "remuneration",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "concession",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "consolidation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Liability (n.) is a debt or obligation; something for which one isliable."
    },
    "187": {
      "Question": "7.187.The local high school issued a ______ on \ufb01eld trips until the buswas repaired; then traveling could begin again.",
      "a": {
        "option": "indispensability",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "divergence",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "moratorium",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "subjection",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "compulsion",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. Moratorium (n.) is a temporary suspension or postponement of aplanned activity."
    },
    "188": {
      "Question": "8.188.With Justine\u2019s ______ nature and passion for art, she would make",
      "a": {
        "option": "volatile",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "congenial",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "servile", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "\ufb02edgling",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "trite", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "b. Congenial (adj.) means having a friendly or pleasant disposition,sociable; having similar tastes, habits, or temperament; suitableto one\u2019s needs or nature."
    },
    "189": {
      "Question": "9.189.Patrice was a(n) ______  girl when she was teenager\u2014long-limbed",
      "a": { "option": "blithe", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "resolute",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "ungainly",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "preternatural",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "conducive",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. Ungainly (adj.) means clumsy or awkward.501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    },
    "190": {
      "Question": "0.190.The employee\u2019s claim of being out with the \ufb02u did not seem very______ because he returned from sick leave with a deep tan.",
      "a": {
        "option": "inattentive",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "inarticulate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "tactful", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "plausible",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "vulnerable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Plausible (adj.) means apparently worthy of belief or praise."
    },
    "191": {
      "Question": "1.191.The con man used his ______ to convince the elderly woman tosign over her life savings to him.",
      "a": { "option": "estuary", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "melee", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "\ufb02agrancy",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "malleability",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "wile", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "e. Wile (n.) means an act or a means of cunning deception."
    },
    "192": {
      "Question": "2.192.Mike proved to be ______ throw after throw, hitting the carnival68",
      "d": {
        "option": "infallible",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "sedentary",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "temporal",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "mediocre",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "infeasible",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Infallible (adj.) means not fallible; completely trustworthy;certain."
    },
    "193": {
      "Question": "3.193.Patrick, who was always joking, added ______ to the formal dinner,which his sedate employer did not appreciate.",
      "a": {
        "option": "contemplation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "ordinance",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "tutelage",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "levity", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "sincerity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Levity (n.) is an inappropriate lack of seriousness or lightness ofmanner; frivolity."
    },
    "194": {
      "Question": "4.194.Sunlight shining through a window was an obvious ______ in thenearly every one of the artist\u2019s works.",
      "a": {
        "option": "disjunction",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "hindrance",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "repugnance",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "motif", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "variance",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Motif (n.) is a recurrent theme or form in an artistic or literarywork."
    },
    "195": {
      "Question": "5.195.I like listening to Wesley go on about politics and social issues; hisopinions are ______ with my own beliefs.",
      "a": { "option": "latent", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "explicit",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "consonant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "ensconced",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "rife", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "c. Consonant (adj.) means in agreement or accord, harmonious;having similar sounds."
    },
    "196": {
      "Question": "6.196.Most people will \ufb01nd the \ufb01lm silly and childish in its humor; themost ______ viewers will \ufb01nd it downright crass and offensive.",
      "a": { "option": "servile", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "petulant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "fastidious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "arcane", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "boisterous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. Fastidious (adj.) means paying careful attention to detail,meticulous; dif\ufb01cult to please, exacting; extremely sensitive,squeamish, especially in regard to matters of cleanliness orpropriety."
    },
    "197": {
      "Question": "7.197.Even though he wanted to win the game, the coach felt that hewould be ______ if he let the injured quarterback continue to play.",
      "a": {
        "option": "contentious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "remiss", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "erudite", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "stringent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "reputable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Remiss (adj.) means careless in performing duties."
    },
    "198": {
      "Question": "8.198.The goal of any company is to have its product name become______\u2014constantly at the forefront of the consumer\u2019s mind.",
      "a": {
        "option": "garrulous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "unctuous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "tremulous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "ubiquitous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "portentous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Ubiquitous (adj.) means being present everywhere."
    },
    "199": {
      "Question": "9.199.During the holiday season, the ______ theme is \u201cPeace on Earth,Goodwill Toward All.\u201d",
      "a": {
        "option": "mitigated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "arrogant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "controversial",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "prevalent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "prestigious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Prevalent (adj.) means widespread or widely accepted;predominant or extensive."
    },
    "200": {
      "Question": "0.200.Our cottage by the sea offers many days of relaxation with warmsunshine and soothing ______.70",
      "a": { "option": "zephyrs", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "dervishes",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "stanchions",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "ebbs", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "torques", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "a. A zephyr is a soft, gentle breeze; a breeze that blows from thewest.72501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    }
  },
  "Chapter 9": {
    "201": {
      "Question": "1.201.When Melinda arrived in the impoverished city, she wasimmediately ______ by bands of children begging for food.",
      "a": {
        "option": "bedraggled",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "accosted",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "in\ufb01ltrated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "rebuked", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "exacerbated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. To accost (v.) means to approach and speak to someone, usuallyin a bold and aggressive manner as with a demand."
    },
    "202": {
      "Question": "2.202.According to the terms of the agreement, if Nicole defaulted onher loan, she would have to ______ her house and car, both whichwould become property of the bank.Chapter 9",
      "a": { "option": "usurp", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "evince", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "debut", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "forfeit", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "stigmatize",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. To forfeit (v.) means to be deprived of or lose the right to by theact of a crime, offense, fault, breach, or error."
    },
    "203": {
      "Question": "3.203.Tony was tired of roommate\u2019s petty ______ about his personal life,so he moved out.",
      "a": {
        "option": "appeasements",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "quips", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "quotas", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "rallies", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "iniquities",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. A quip (n.) is a sarcastic or cutting jest; a witty remark."
    },
    "204": {
      "Question": "4.204.The food at the buffet table was a ______ array of delights that",
      "e": {
        "option": "tantalizing",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "tempestuous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "tantamount",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "truculent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "temporal",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. Tantalizing (adj.) means tempting, attractive, often via thesenses."
    },
    "205": {
      "Question": "5.205.After \ufb01ghting the \ufb01ve-alarm \ufb01re, the ______ \ufb01re\ufb01ghter could notrelax enough to unwind and get some rest.",
      "a": {
        "option": "amicable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "treacherous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "pliable", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "durable", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "overwrought",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. Overwrought (adj.) means labored to excess; anxious, agitated."
    },
    "206": {
      "Question": "6.206.For years Henry bore the ______ of being the only man in \ufb01vegenerations of his family not to make the varsity baseball team.74",
      "a": { "option": "stigma", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "brunt", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "treatise",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "scintillation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "punctiliousness",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Stigma means a mark of infamy or token of disgrace."
    },
    "207": {
      "Question": "7.207.Tabitha found an overpriced dining table at the antique shop andtried to ______ with the shopkeeper, but he refused to lower theprice.",
      "a": { "option": "haggle", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "stipulate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "annunciate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "ruminate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "confer", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "a. To haggle (v.) means to bargain, such as over a price, or disputein a petty way; to wrangle."
    },
    "208": {
      "Question": "8.208.The \ufb01re\ufb01ghter was ______ in the news for his heroic rescue of a",
      "c": {
        "option": "reconstituted",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "mandated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "inferred",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "augmented",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "lauded", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "e. To laud (v.) is to praise, honor, or glorify."
    },
    "209": {
      "Question": "9.209.Although she was on a diet, Hannah intended to ______ in thefeast of Thanksgiving.",
      "a": { "option": "dilate", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "enervate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "expunge", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "nullify", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "partake", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "e. To partake (v.) is to have a share or take part."
    },
    "210": {
      "Question": "0.210.The villagers locked their doors when they heard about the pirateswho were ______ unprotected villages along the island\u2019s coastline.",
      "a": {
        "option": "reforming",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "marauding",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "reclaiming",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "conceding",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "recapitulating",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. To maraud (v.) is to rove and raid in quest of plunder."
    },
    "211": {
      "Question": "1.211.I could tell by Angelica\u2019s ______ tone that she was still very angrywith me.",
      "a": {
        "option": "ingratiating",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "adjacent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "oblique", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "acerbic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "eloquent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Acerbic (adj.) means sour or bitter in taste; sharp or biting intone, character, or expression."
    },
    "212": {
      "Question": "2.212.After years of living at a(n) ______ pace, Paola decided it was timeto slow down and learn how to relax.",
      "a": {
        "option": "frenetic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "pedestrian",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "pretentious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "colloquial",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "insipid", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "a. Frenetic (adj.) means wildly excited or agitated, frenzied, frantic."
    },
    "213": {
      "Question": "3.213.The hospital had an outbreak of chicken pox and was forced to______ all patients and staff to prevent more infected victims.",
      "a": {
        "option": "clandestine",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "saturate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "germinate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "quarantine",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "aggregate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. To quarantine (v.) means to restrict the entrance to and exit fromany place under observation for infectious disease."
    },
    "214": {
      "Question": "4.214.Living on several acres of land dotted with oak and maple treesmakes autumn leaf-raking a ______ task.",
      "a": { "option": "fatuous", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "toilsome",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "tardy", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "obsequious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "fawning", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "b. Toilsome (adj.) means laborious or hard work."
    },
    "215": {
      "Question": "5.215.Acting in the high school play served to ______ Ander\u2019s appetitefor professional acting.76",
      "a": { "option": "satiate", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "whet", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "purport", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "incriminate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "corral", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "b. To whet (v.) means to make more keen or eager.80501 Sentence Completion Questions81"
    },
    "216": {
      "Question": "6.216.It would take many hours of cleaning and repairing for the youngfamily to transform the ______ into a clean and comfortable little",
      "c": { "option": "hovel", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": {
        "option": "territory",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "manor", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "demesne", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "hacienda",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. A hovel (n.) is a small crude house; a \ufb01lthy or disorganized hutor shed."
    },
    "217": {
      "Question": "7.217.Ms. Lu allowed her son a great deal of ______ in spending his",
      "b": {
        "option": "assimilation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "injunction",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "latitude",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "declamation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "stimulus",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. Latitude (n.) is freedom from normal limitations or restraints inconduct; an angular distance from a plane of reference."
    },
    "218": {
      "Question": "8.218.It was once believed that alchemists could ______ common metalsto gold.",
      "a": {
        "option": "transmute",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "commute", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "execute", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "repute", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "denote", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "a. To transmute (v.) means to change in nature, substance, or form."
    },
    "219": {
      "Question": "9.219.The close-up of the actor drinking the popular brand of cola in themovie was a ______ display of commercialism.",
      "a": {
        "option": "dispassionate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "languid", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "apathetic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "gratuitous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "unpunctual",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Gratuitous (adj.) means unjusti\ufb01ed or unnecessary; of no cost."
    },
    "220": {
      "Question": "0.220.Juneod was ______ after his alibi proved that he could not have",
      "c": { "option": "derided", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": {
        "option": "acquitted",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "protracted",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "denounced",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "acquainted",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. To acquit (v.) means to free or clear from an accusation orcharge; to release or discharge from a duty, obligation, or debt;to behave oneself in a certain manner."
    },
    "221": {
      "Question": "1.221.This summer\u2019s movies are ______ for audiences of escape-the-heatmindless entertainment\u2014not one \ufb01lm offers a substantive or evenplausible plot.",
      "a": {
        "option": "privation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "dulcet", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "jargon", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "fodder", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "germane", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "d. Fodder (n.) is a consumable, often inferior resource or item, highin demand and usually abundant in supply."
    },
    "222": {
      "Question": "2.222.The dictator used propaganda and intimidation to ______ therevolution.",
      "a": { "option": "prelude", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "intimate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "congregate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "irradiate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "quell", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "e. To quell (v.) means to cease or suppress."
    },
    "223": {
      "Question": "3.223.Standing on the ______, the preacher greeted the parishioners78",
      "e": { "option": "sensor", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": { "option": "steeple", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "pillar", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "parvis", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "manifestation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. A parvis (n.) is the porch or area before a building (as a church)."
    },
    "224": {
      "Question": "4.224.Simona\u2019s ______ with her money caught up with her when she",
      "d": {
        "option": "intuition",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "miserliness",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "thriftiness",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "wantonness",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "predilection",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. Wantonness (n.) means recklessness; bawdy; merciless."
    },
    "225": {
      "Question": "5.225.The architect designed the ceiling using wood ______ that wouldremain uncovered, creating a rustic ambience in the living room.",
      "a": {
        "option": "pediments",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "joists", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "mullions",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "banisters",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "abutments",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Joist (n.) is a small, horizontal beam that supports a ceiling or\ufb02oor, usually made of wood, reinforced concrete, or steel.501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    }
  },
  "Chapter 10": {
    "226": {
      "Question": "6.226.When the house on the corner burned down, the entireneighborhood ______ together to help to the victims re-establishtheir lives.",
      "a": { "option": "rallied", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "recited", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "skulked", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "disintegrated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "expedited",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. To rally (v.) means to come together for a common purpose oras a means of support; to recover or rebound."
    },
    "227": {
      "Question": "7.227.The massage therapist\u2019s ______ \ufb01ngers quickly eased the tension inBlanche\u2019s back.Chapter 10",
      "a": { "option": "deft", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "furtive", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "listless",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "tentative",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "blithe", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "a. Deft (adj.) means quick and skillful in movement, adroit."
    },
    "228": {
      "Question": "8.228.Jade\u2019s parents were in ______ about the decision not to allow herto drive the family car to the prom; they both agreed that it would",
      "b": { "option": "redress", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": {
        "option": "af\ufb02uence",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "refraction",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "discord", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "unison", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "e. Unison (n.) means a condition of perfect agreement and accord."
    },
    "229": {
      "Question": "9.229.As she walked through the halls of her old grade school, Madeline",
      "b": {
        "option": "nostalgic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "proli\ufb01c",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "credulous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "precocious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "ambitious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Nostalgic (adj.) is sentimentally yearning for a point in the past."
    },
    "230": {
      "Question": "0.230.After being cleared of all charges for slander, the attorney was ableto go back to work and ______ his role as a prosecutor.",
      "a": { "option": "inhibit", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "reprimand",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "remand", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "resume", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "dissipate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. To resume (v.) means to take up again after interruption."
    },
    "231": {
      "Question": "1.231.Ignacio\u2019s pain was so ______ that he called 911.",
      "a": { "option": "remiss", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "rapacious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "genteel", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "resolute",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "acute", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "e. Acute (adj.) means extremely sharp or intense; keenly perceptiveor discerning; of great importance or consequence, crucial; also,having a sharp tip or point."
    },
    "232": {
      "Question": "2.232.The captain ______ the cargo to keep his ship a\ufb02oat.84",
      "a": { "option": "rebuked", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "listed", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "disunited",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "\ufb02anked",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "jettisoned",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. To jettison (v.) is to toss goods overboard to lighten the load of aship or aircraft to improve stability; to toss off (a burden)."
    },
    "233": {
      "Question": "3.233.The teacher tried to ______ her class of their dependence on thenumber lines pasted to the tops of their desks.",
      "a": { "option": "wane", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "wax", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "whet", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "wean", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "wield", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "d. To wean (v.) means to detach someone from that to which he isaccustomed or devoted."
    },
    "234": {
      "Question": "4.234.The young girl was so full of enthusiasm and ______ that sheinfected the room with energy.",
      "a": {
        "option": "languidness",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "apathy", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "vivacity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "blandness",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "tenacity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. Vivacity (n.) means liveliness, to be \ufb01ll of life."
    },
    "235": {
      "Question": "5.235.Ricky is a ______ of the local coffee shop; you can \ufb01nd him therejust about every morning.",
      "a": { "option": "diva", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "relic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "denizen", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "maverick",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "pariah", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "c. A denizen (n.) is one who frequents a particular place; one wholives in a particular place, an inhabitant."
    },
    "236": {
      "Question": "6.236.The child danced with ______ joy at hearing the news that herfather had arrived home from his lengthy business trip.",
      "a": { "option": "staid", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "unbridled",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "stealthy",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "bene\ufb01cial",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "restrained",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Unbridled (adj.) means without restraint."
    },
    "237": {
      "Question": "7.237.Having never left the landlocked Midwest his entire life, Albertfound that swimming in the ocean was quite a(n) ______.",
      "a": {
        "option": "familiarity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "extrovert",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "instinct",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "novelty", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "tabernacle",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. A novelty (n.) is a new or unusual thing or occurrence."
    },
    "238": {
      "Question": "8.238.The rowdy crowd at the music concert ______ Herve, and hespilled his soda on his pants.",
      "a": {
        "option": "jettisoned",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "harrowed",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "jostled", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "lauded", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "superceded",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. To jostle (v.) is to push or shove roughly against; to drive withpushing; to disturb or bump."
    },
    "239": {
      "Question": "9.239.Known for his strong command of the courtroom, it was commonknowledge that Judge Disantis considered outbursts from",
      "d": { "option": "pliable", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": {
        "option": "questionable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "objectionable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "antisocial",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "visionary",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Objectionable (adj.) means unpleasant or offensive."
    },
    "240": {
      "Question": "0.240.Blinded by ______, Nicholas accepted the job offer with thehighest pay but the least possibility of making him happy.",
      "a": { "option": "ennui", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "heresy", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "infamy", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "avarice", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "temperance",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Avarice (n.) means an excessive or insatiable desire for materialwealth; inordinate greed.501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    },
    "241": {
      "Question": "1.241.It was very unprofessional of you to ______ your assistant in frontof everyone at the meeting; she deserves more respect, and any86",
      "c": { "option": "usurp", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": { "option": "placate", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "augment", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "preclude",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "deride", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "e. To deride (v.) is to speak of or treat with contempt; to ridiculescornfully."
    },
    "242": {
      "Question": "2. The log cabin had a(n) ______ feel, so it was often enjoyed by242. The log cabin had a(n) ______ feel, so it was often enjoyed byvacationers from the city throughout the year.",
      "a": {
        "option": "abstract",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "ersatz", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "rustic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "raucous", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "repellent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. Rustic (adj.) means rural; rough; made from rough limbs ortrees."
    },
    "243": {
      "Question": "3.243.We knew Jana had ______ motives for running for class president:She wanted the nearby parking space that came with the of\ufb01ce.",
      "a": {
        "option": "anterior",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "interior",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "inferior",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "posterior",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "ulterior",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. Ulterior (adj.) means lying beyond or outside what is openlyshown or said."
    },
    "244": {
      "Question": "4.244.The town board heard many outraged and ______ arguments fromthe citizens against the destruction of some wooded areas in orderto build a new mall.",
      "a": { "option": "tenuous", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "vociferous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "vacuous", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "satis\ufb01ed",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "egregious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Vociferous (adj.) means making a loud outcry."
    },
    "245": {
      "Question": "5.245.The villainous gang\u2019s hideout was a den of ______ that no onewould dare to enter.",
      "a": {
        "option": "innocence",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "habitants",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "iniquity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "accolades",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "innovation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. Iniquity (n.) is wickedness or overwhelming injustice."
    },
    "246": {
      "Question": "6.246.Indigestion is a common ______ of participating in a hot-dog",
      "e": {
        "option": "itinerary",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "euphemism",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "penchant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "corollary",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "juxtaposition",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. Corollary (n.) means a natural consequence or result; adeduction or inference that follows from the proof of anotherproposition."
    },
    "247": {
      "Question": "7.247.Although it was so ridiculous that no one believed it to be true, thereporter\u2019s ______ still cost the governor his re-election.",
      "a": {
        "option": "hegemony",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "sedition",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "malaise", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "compendium",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "calumny", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "e. Calumny (n.) means a false statement or accusation utteredmaliciously to harm another\u2019s reputation, slander."
    },
    "248": {
      "Question": "8.248.People on the street stopped to ______ over the artist\u2019s renditionof the Eiffel Tower, amazed by his ability to capture the detail.",
      "a": {
        "option": "bedazzle",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "innovate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "gratify", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "counteract",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "objectify",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. To objectify (v.) means to stare at amorously."
    },
    "249": {
      "Question": "9.249.The veteran lieutenant was not happy with his ______ rank behindthe two inexperienced men.",
      "a": {
        "option": "tertiary",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "silly", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "unctuous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "superior",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "fastened",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Tertiary (adj.) ranking third in order of importance, position, orvalue."
    },
    "250": {
      "Question": "0.250.The prime minister was admired by all, a(n) ______ even in an88",
      "e": {
        "option": "profanation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "admonishment",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "alleviation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "nonpareil",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "prototype",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. A nonpareil (n.) is a person or thing of peerless excellence.90501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    }
  },
  "Chapter 11": {
    "251": {
      "Question": "1.251.The queen\u2019s ______ fell ill during his journey and was unable tonegotiate on her behalf when he arrived at the economic summit.",
      "a": { "option": "penury", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "miscreant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "emissary",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "denizen", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "zealot", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "c. An emissary (n.) is an agent sent on a mission to represent theinterests of someone else."
    },
    "252": {
      "Question": "2.252.Tai was ______ by a series of setbacks that nearly made him misshis deadline.Chapter 11",
      "a": {
        "option": "ensconced",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "relegated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "beleaguered",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "solicited",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "winnowed",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. To beleaguer (v.) is to harass, beset, besiege."
    },
    "253": {
      "Question": "3.253.New York boasts many ______ restaurants\u2014places that are elegant",
      "a": { "option": "pungent", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "middling",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "posh", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "diminutive",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "mediocre",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Posh (adj.) means elegant and fashionable."
    },
    "254": {
      "Question": "4.254.Patsy was shocked to discover how much higher her IQ was thanthe ______.",
      "a": { "option": "norm", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "stimulation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "prudence",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "solitude",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "derivative",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. A norm (n.) is an average standard, pattern, or type."
    },
    "255": {
      "Question": "5.255.Although she appeared con\ufb01dent, once she began her speech, thevaledictorian\u2019s ______ voice indicated her nervousness.",
      "a": {
        "option": "supercilious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "resonant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "tenuous", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "placating",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "tremulous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. Tremulous (adj.) means characterized by quivering orunsteadiness."
    },
    "256": {
      "Question": "6.256.Danielle cannot seem to \ufb01nd her niche in life; she has changed her______ at least three times in the past ten years.92",
      "a": {
        "option": "automation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "vocation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "plethora",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "pliancy", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "combustion",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Vocation (n.) means a regular occupation or profession."
    },
    "257": {
      "Question": "7.257.The discovery of the new element was ______; the scientist waslooking for something else.",
      "a": {
        "option": "insigni\ufb01cant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "intrepid",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "eloquent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "inadvertent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "emollient",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Inadvertent (adj.) means not attentive or heedless; actingcarelessly; unintentional."
    },
    "258": {
      "Question": "8.258.A charming painting of a pleasant ______ landscape hung aboveVitaly\u2019s \ufb01replace, in marked contrast to the noise and lights of the",
      "b": {
        "option": "histrionic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": { "option": "nascent", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "bucolic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "indigenous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "ersatz", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "c. Bucolic (adj.) means of or characteristic of country life or people,rustic, especially in an idealized sense; of or characteristic ofshepherds or herdsmen, pastoral."
    },
    "259": {
      "Question": "9.259.Aidan, who has always been painfully shy, was very ______ by thenews that he would have to do a presentation in front of his",
      "c": {
        "option": "relegated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "discom\ufb01ted",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "circumvented",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "promulgated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "castigated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. To discom\ufb01t (v.) means to make uneasy, disconcert; to cause tolose one\u2019s composure; to break up or thwart the plans of,frustrate."
    },
    "260": {
      "Question": "0.260.Since his parents had little money, Peter was ______ to his unclefor paying for his college education.",
      "a": { "option": "alleged", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "provided",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "obliged", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "demented",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "forti\ufb01ed",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. Obliged (v.) means to be indebted."
    },
    "261": {
      "Question": "1.261.With great ______, we stepped gingerly onto the planks of the",
      "d": {
        "option": "refraction",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "trepidation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "instigation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "perdition",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "endowment",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Trepidation (n.) means nervous uncertainty of feeling."
    },
    "262": {
      "Question": "2.262.At the risk of sounding like an ______, the teacher assigned extrahomework for the weekend.",
      "a": { "option": "oaf", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "ogre", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "impost", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "alcove", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "anathema",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. An ogre (n.) is, in popular usage, a cruel person, or a monster."
    },
    "263": {
      "Question": "3.263.Felix felt that his mother\u2019s request to run her errands was a huge______ since he would have rather watched a soccer match with hisfriends that afternoon.",
      "a": {
        "option": "justi\ufb01cation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "imposition",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "preponderance",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "deviation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "recourse",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Imposition (n.) is the act of imposing something such as a burdenor duty; an unfair demand."
    },
    "264": {
      "Question": "4.264.The paper was ______ so that it could be easily removed from the94",
      "b": {
        "option": "infectious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "voracious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "\ufb01ckle",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "perforated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "\ufb02uent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Perforated (adj.) means with a line of holes to facilitateseparation; pierced with a pointed instrument.98501 Sentence Completion Questions99"
    },
    "265": {
      "Question": "5.265.The mad scientist ______ the potion with acid, making it not onlyuseless, but also dangerous.",
      "a": {
        "option": "corrugated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "vitiated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "implemented",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "instigated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "titillated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. To vitiate (v.) means to spoil; to make faulty or impure; tocorrupt morally."
    },
    "266": {
      "Question": "6.266.Jayne\u2019s paintings were not minimalist, but they were ______, usingonly the most elemental and essential elements.",
      "a": {
        "option": "elliptical",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "truculent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "pernicious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "perfunctory",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "abstemious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Elliptical (adj.) means characterized by extreme economy ofwords or style; of, relating to, or having the shape of an ellipsis."
    },
    "267": {
      "Question": "7.267.Wendell\u2019s prolonged illness was the ______ that ignited his interestin science and led to his illustrious career in medical research.",
      "a": {
        "option": "hyperbole",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "catalyst",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "penchant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "insolence",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "caveat", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "or event; (in chemistry) a substance that initiates or accelerates achemical reaction without itself being affected in the process."
    },
    "268": {
      "Question": "8.268.Stopping to admire the ______ in the front yard, the young woman",
      "c": { "option": "clutter", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": {
        "option": "paradigm",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "compost", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "oleander",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "patagium",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. An oleander (n.) is a beautiful but poisonous evergreen shrub."
    },
    "269": {
      "Question": "9.269.The river, ______ with new-fallen rain, over\ufb02owed its banks and\ufb02ooded the tiny village in a matter of hours.",
      "a": {
        "option": "placated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "turgid", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "redundant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "equivalent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "quarantined",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Turgid (adj.) means swollen."
    },
    "270": {
      "Question": "0.270.In a(n) ______ expression of pleasure, the infant clapped her hands",
      "a": { "option": "overt", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "obligatory",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "illusive",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "peremptory",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "turbulent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      }
    },
    "271": {
      "Question": "1.271.Paula\u2019s ______ humor does not amuse many people; rather many\ufb01nd it offensive and hurtful.",
      "a": {
        "option": "nebulous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "truncated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "stoic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "vitriolic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "\ufb02irtatious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Vitriolic (adj.) means bitterly scathing; caustic."
    },
    "272": {
      "Question": "2.272.The play\u2019s ______ debut was not a good sign for the strugglingproducer.",
      "a": {
        "option": "unsubstantial",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "inauspicious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "copious", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "disembodied",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "immaterial",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Inauspicious (adj.) means not favorable or unfortunate; notpromising success."
    },
    "273": {
      "Question": "3.273.At one time it was in ______ for women to wear gloves and hatswhenever they were out in public.",
      "a": { "option": "gore", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "gauge", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "vogue", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "brawn", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "vain", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "c. Vogue (n.) means the prevalent way or fashion."
    },
    "274": {
      "Question": "4.274.To ensure that Brenda wouldn\u2019t know where we were going for her96",
      "b": { "option": "craven", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": { "option": "ardent", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "enigmatic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "circuitous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "mercurial",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Circuitous (adj.) means having or taking a roundabout, lengthy,or indirect course."
    },
    "275": {
      "Question": "5.275.The editorial was essentially a(n) ______ to the governor, praisingher for her enactment of a series of environmental laws and for",
      "b": {
        "option": "imprecation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "juggernaut",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "cabal", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "oeuvre", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "encomium",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. Encomium (n.) means a formal expression of praise, a glowingtribute.501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    }
  },
  "Chapter 12": {
    "276": {
      "Question": "6.276.Claude felt particularly ______ as he carried the large satchel \ufb01lledwith cash through the dark streets to the bank.",
      "a": {
        "option": "inclusive",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "vulnerable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "reclusive",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "unwieldy",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "torrential",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Vulnerable (adj.) means assailable; capable of receiving injuries;open to attack."
    },
    "277": {
      "Question": "7.277.Niall\u2019s ______ attitude toward the boss is embarrassing; he doesnearly everything for him except scratch his nose!Chapter 12",
      "a": {
        "option": "subservient",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "subversive",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "subtle", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "sundry", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "surly", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "a. Subservient (adj.) means following another\u2019s requests in aservantlike manner far below that which is called for."
    },
    "278": {
      "Question": "8.278.Although she was a successful professional, Debra\u2019s inability to",
      "a": { "option": "endowed", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "rapturous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "ravenous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "obtuse", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "elated", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "d. Obtuse (adj.) means lacking quickness of perception or intellect."
    },
    "279": {
      "Question": "9.279.Jeremy didn\u2019t want to appear ______, but his brothers simply couldnot convince him to change his mind.",
      "a": { "option": "pitiful", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "scrupulous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "harmonious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "obstinate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "unabated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Obstinate (adj.) means stubborn."
    },
    "280": {
      "Question": "0.280.Buying homeowner\u2019s insurance is a wise decision because itprovides ______ if your house should be damaged in a \ufb01re.",
      "a": {
        "option": "chastisement",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "indemnity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "clari\ufb01cation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "resolution",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "annulment",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Indemnity (n.) is protection from loss or damage; immunity frompunishment; compensation for loss or damage."
    },
    "281": {
      "Question": "1.281.Although it was supposed to be written for the general public, thereport was so ______ that only those with inside knowledge ofgovernment workings could understand it.102",
      "a": {
        "option": "indigenous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "ebullient",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "truculent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "pugnacious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "esoteric",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. Esoteric (adj.) means designed for, con\ufb01ned to, orunderstandable only by a restricted number of people, anenlightened inner circle."
    },
    "282": {
      "Question": "2.282.Todd set up a rope to ______ the part of the exhibit that was off-limits.",
      "a": {
        "option": "circumscribe",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "laud", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "efface", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "undulate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "beguile", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "a. To circumscribe (v.) is to draw a line around, encircle; to restrictor con\ufb01ne; to determine the limits of, de\ufb01ne."
    },
    "283": {
      "Question": "3.283.The loud clap of thunder caused the little dog to ______ all over.",
      "a": { "option": "slather", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "quake", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "enunciate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "binge", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "infuse", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "b. To quake (v.) means to shiver or tremble, as from fear or cold; toshake or vibrate violently."
    },
    "284": {
      "Question": "4.284.Francois fell into a groggy ______ after having suffered a highfever for several days.",
      "a": {
        "option": "profundity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "sluggard",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "verve", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "stupor", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "grovel", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "d. Stupor (n.) means profound lethargy, such as one mightexperience after being very ill."
    },
    "285": {
      "Question": "5.285.Blaine had a tendency to ______ certain details of his evenings outwhen he didn\u2019t want his parents to know where he had been.",
      "a": { "option": "excel", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "oscillate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "corroborate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "juxtapose",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "omit", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "e. To omit (v.) is to leave out; to neglect, disregard."
    },
    "286": {
      "Question": "6.286.We took pity on the young ______ and brought him to a shelterwhere he could \ufb01nd food and warmth.",
      "a": { "option": "waif", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "per\ufb01dy",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "ionic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "plaintiff",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "troubadour",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. A waif (n.) is a stray; a homeless, neglected wanderer, especiallya homeless child."
    },
    "287": {
      "Question": "7.287.The \ufb01re caused ______ damage to the warehouse, which forced theowner to demolish the building.",
      "a": {
        "option": "sancti\ufb01ed",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "equitable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "preliminary",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "irreparable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "pretentious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Irreparable (adj.) means not capable of being remedied orcorrected; not reparable."
    },
    "288": {
      "Question": "8.288.When people are in love, they may \ufb01nd their beloved\u2019s ______\u2014often annoying to or disparaged by others\u2014to be charming and",
      "e": {
        "option": "penchants",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": { "option": "foibles", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "mendacity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "ennui", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "aplomb", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "a. A foible (n.) is a minor weakness or character \ufb02aw; a distinctivebehavior or attribute peculiar to an individual.501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    },
    "289": {
      "Question": "9.289.Terreh was able to ______ the traf\ufb01c jam by taking a series of one-way streets that led to the bridge.",
      "a": { "option": "staunch", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "diffuse", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "corroborate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "circumvent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "juxtapose",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. To circumvent (v.) is to go around, bypass; to get around or avoidthrough cleverness or artful maneuvering; to surround, enclose,entrap."
    },
    "290": {
      "Question": "0.290.The risk of cheating on the test was not worth the possible ______of failing the class.104",
      "a": {
        "option": "speci\ufb01cation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "grati\ufb01cation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "rami\ufb01cation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "narcissism",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "renegade",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. A rami\ufb01cation (n.) is a consequence for an action."
    },
    "291": {
      "Question": "1.291.We found that the gallons of water we had brought on our hikewere ______, and we had to carry the extra bottles home.",
      "a": {
        "option": "superannuated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "extraordinary",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "derivative",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "super\ufb02uous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "untenable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Super\ufb02uous (adj.) means extra; more than is needed, unnecessary."
    },
    "292": {
      "Question": "2.292.Moving all the heavy cinder blocks by hand from the driveway tothe backyard seemed like a(n) ______ task.",
      "a": {
        "option": "precipitous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "poignant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "onerous", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "salient", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "gallant", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "c. Onerous (adj.) is burdensome or troublesome."
    },
    "293": {
      "Question": "3.293.Claudia\u2019s ______ face gave no clue to her hard, cold heart.",
      "a": { "option": "winsome", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "gruesome",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "fatuous", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "ironic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "\ufb02accid",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Winsome (adj.) means attractive."
    },
    "294": {
      "Question": "4.294.Keeping hot peppers in the olive oil ______ it with a spicy kick.",
      "a": {
        "option": "contemplates",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "stigmatizes",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "scrutinizes",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "infuses", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "defames", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "d. To infuse (v.) is to instill or cause to penetrate; to inspire."
    },
    "295": {
      "Question": "5.295.She realized mortgage rates had declined and decided it was______ to continue paying rent when she could now afford amonthly payment for her own home.",
      "a": {
        "option": "referable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "relative",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "subsequent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "episodic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "inexpedient",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. Inexpedient (adj.) means not expedient; not suitable or \ufb01t for thepurpose; not tending to promote a proposed object."
    },
    "296": {
      "Question": "6.296.The deadline has been moved to this Friday, so we must ______our efforts and complete the project earlier than we had planned.",
      "a": { "option": "wane", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "ruminate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "burnish", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "pilfer", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "expedite",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. To expedite (v.) means to speed up the progress of, accelerate; toprocess or execute quickly and ef\ufb01ciently."
    },
    "297": {
      "Question": "7.297.As the city grew and stretched its borders, it began to feel the______ problems of urban sprawl and overpopulation.",
      "a": {
        "option": "improvident",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "mendacious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "ersatz", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "concomitant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "surreptitious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Concomitant (adj.) means occurring or existing concurrently;accompanying, attendant."
    },
    "298": {
      "Question": "8.298.Terrance, a dentist, ______ to be with the media, so he could seethe concert for free.",
      "a": {
        "option": "facilitated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "conjugated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "purported",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "tended", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "placated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. To purport (v.) means to give false appearance of being."
    },
    "299": {
      "Question": "9.299.______ on a lounge chair by the pool was the very tan owner of the",
      "e": { "option": "Supine", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": { "option": "Trident", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "Renegade",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "Fraught", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "Renowned",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. Supine (adj.) means lying on the back."
    },
    "300": {
      "Question": "0.300.Observing his sister\u2019s ______ behavior of riding without a helmet,Jorge ran to get his mother.106",
      "a": {
        "option": "contemptuous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "contented",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "\ufb01ctitious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "parlous", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "pensive", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "d. Parlous (adj.) means dangerous, risky, or extreme.108501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    }
  },
  "Chapter 13": {
    "301": {
      "Question": "1.301.In an attempt to ______ the enemy, Braveheart rallied hundreds of\ufb01erce warriors.",
      "a": {
        "option": "alienate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "scoff", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "obliterate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "ostracize",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "minimize",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. To obliterate (v.) means to blot out or destroy."
    },
    "302": {
      "Question": "2.302.The \ufb01lm was completed on schedule despite the ______Chapter 13",
      "c": { "option": "cryptic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": { "option": "tenuous", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "imperial",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "contrived",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "adverse", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "e. Adverse (adj.) means acting against or contrary to; unfavorable;or opposed or opposing."
    },
    "303": {
      "Question": "3.303.The postcard advertised a free cruise to anyone who bought amagazine subscription, but after reading the \ufb01ne print Sasha foundthe cruise was just a ______.",
      "a": {
        "option": "petition",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "gimmick", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "compromise",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "reference",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "motif", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "b. A gimmick (n.) is a tricky scheme or gadget."
    },
    "304": {
      "Question": "4.304.Many employers like to visit college campuses and ______ collegeseniors to work for their companies.",
      "a": { "option": "daunt", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "recruit", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "illuminate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "dither", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "\ufb02out",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. To recruit (v.) means to seek to induct or enroll; to enlist."
    },
    "305": {
      "Question": "5.305.I could tell by Konrad\u2019s ______ manner that he was really sorry forhow he had treated Annette.",
      "a": { "option": "callous", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "erratic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "zealous", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "nonchalant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "contrite",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. Contrite (adj.) means feeling or expressing sorrow or regret forone\u2019s sins or offenses; penitent."
    },
    "306": {
      "Question": "6.306.The company of\ufb01cials felt the rising cost of health coverage was______ enough to raise their employees\u2019 insurance premiums.",
      "a": {
        "option": "moratorium",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "justi\ufb01cation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "symbolism",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "disposition",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "habitude",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Justi\ufb01cation (n.) is an explanation or reason that justi\ufb01es orshows something to be necessary."
    },
    "307": {
      "Question": "7.307.The ______ of the sheriff\u2019s department ended at the county line.110",
      "a": {
        "option": "prerequisite",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "emendation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "alliteration",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "jurisdiction",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "respite", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "d. Jurisdiction (n.) is authority or power; sphere of power orauthority."
    },
    "308": {
      "Question": "8.308.Ralph plays golf every chance he gets; even a weeklong gol\ufb01ngvacation could not ______ his appetite for the game.",
      "a": {
        "option": "initiate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "satiate", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "relinquish",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "revive", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "employ", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "b. To satiate (v.) means to satisfy fully the appetite or desire of."
    },
    "309": {
      "Question": "9.309.We could not describe the scene before us; it was \ufb01lled with such______ beauty.",
      "a": {
        "option": "inexorable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "unutterable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "uproarious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "mnemonic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "fretful", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "b. Unutterable (adj.) means inexpressible."
    },
    "310": {
      "Question": "0.310.The subject matter was ______ because the mumbling professorspoke too quickly.",
      "a": { "option": "obscure", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "magnanimous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "treacherous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "vital", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "maximized",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Obscure (adj.) means not clearly expressed or easily understood;not easily seen or distinguished."
    },
    "311": {
      "Question": "1.311.Arnie becomes so ______ when he talks about painting that it ishard not to be infected by his enthusiasm.",
      "a": { "option": "laconic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "circuitous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "impertinent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "ardent", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "recalcitrant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Ardent (adj.) means characterized by intense emotion orenthusiasm, passionate, fervent; glowing or burning like \ufb01re."
    },
    "312": {
      "Question": "2.312.The cruise ship\u2019s deliciously appetizing dinner buffets encouraged______ among the vacationing passengers.",
      "a": {
        "option": "gluttony",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "squabbling",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "equivocation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "restraint",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "queries", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "a. Gluttony (n.) is drinking or eating to excess; excessiveindulgence."
    },
    "313": {
      "Question": "3.313.As the pressures of her business became overwhelming, Charlotte",
      "c": {
        "option": "propagate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "expedite",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "transgress",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "relinquish",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "retaliate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. To relinquish (v.) means to give up (something), renounce claimto."
    },
    "314": {
      "Question": "4.314.Don\u2019t let Julie\u2019s enthusiasm fool you; she\u2019s just a ______, not aprofessional dancer.",
      "a": {
        "option": "maverick",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "denizen", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "mercenary",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "maven", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "dilettante",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. A dilettante (n.) is an amateur, one who dabbles in an art or \ufb01eldof knowledge for amusement; a lover of \ufb01ne arts, a connoisseur.501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    },
    "315": {
      "Question": "5.315.Normally, Maya would not have made so many spelling mistakes inher essay; she is usually ______ about her spelling.",
      "a": {
        "option": "sumptuous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "scurrilous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "ridiculous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "scrupulous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "fatuous", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "d. Scrupulous (adj.) means extremely careful, cautious in action forfear of doing wrong."
    },
    "316": {
      "Question": "6.316.It took four men two hours to move the ______ sofa up three\ufb02ights of stairs into our apartment.",
      "a": { "option": "suave", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "garrulous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "unwieldy",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "pivotal", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "quixotic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. Unwieldy (adj.) means moved or managed with dif\ufb01culty, asfrom great size or awkward shape."
    },
    "317": {
      "Question": "7.317.In the Roman myth, Artemis made a pilgrimage to the ______,hoping to learn the answer to her dilemma.112",
      "a": {
        "option": "denouement",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "decorum", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "oracle", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "vizier", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "pillar", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "c. An oracle (n.) is a person of great knowledge; the place whereanswers are given, as in a sanctuary."
    },
    "318": {
      "Question": "8.318.Orson was truly a(n) ______: towering over others at six feet nineinches, he was also one of the most in\ufb02uential and successfulproducers in the feature \ufb01lm industry.",
      "a": {
        "option": "behemoth",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "anathema",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "demagogue",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "viceroy", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "charlatan",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. A behemoth (n.) is a giant; something or someone who isenormous in size, power, or importance."
    },
    "319": {
      "Question": "9.319.Brian was an ______ child, he was sent to the principal\u2019s of\ufb01ce onnumerous occasions for his rude classroom behavior.",
      "a": {
        "option": "impeccable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "impertinent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "observant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "obscure", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "adjuvant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Impertinent (adj.) means improperly bold; rude; lacking goodmanners."
    },
    "320": {
      "Question": "0.320.The defendant waited anxiously for the jury to ______ the decisionthat would seal his fate.",
      "a": { "option": "render", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "deprecate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "rejuvenate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "disparage",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "prohibit",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. To render (v.) means to give in return in compliance with a duty;to make or depict."
    },
    "321": {
      "Question": "1.321.We must ______ the information about the agenda changesimmediately so that the conference attendees have time to adjusttheir schedules.",
      "a": { "option": "burnish", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "disseminate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "galvanize",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "placate", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "admonish",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. To disseminate (v.) means to scatter widely, diffuse, spreadabroad."
    },
    "322": {
      "Question": "2.322.During the time of the plague in the little village, the forlorn______ of the church bells was an almost daily sound.",
      "a": {
        "option": "prepossession",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "premise", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "delectation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "knell", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "credence",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Knell (n.) is the sound of a bell ringing slowly for a funeral ordeath."
    },
    "323": {
      "Question": "3.323.If you can adhere to the ______ rules of a military society, theMarines may be an excellent career choice.",
      "a": {
        "option": "strident",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "raucous", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "stringent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "pedantic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "lurid", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "c. Stringent (adj.) means rigid, strict, or exacting."
    },
    "324": {
      "Question": "4.324.The natural ______ of the canyon cause it to be an everlastingsource of new adventures and beauty.",
      "a": {
        "option": "blandishments",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "vicissitudes",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "mores", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "platitudes",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "nebulas", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "b. Vicissitudes (n.) means a change, especially a complete change, ofcondition or circumstances."
    },
    "325": {
      "Question": "5.325.A life-long vegetarian, Xiomara ______ when she learned that thesauce she\u2019d just eaten was made with chicken broth.114",
      "a": { "option": "wavered", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "blanched",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "coalesced",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "stagnated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "thwarted",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. To blanch (v.) means to turn pale, as if in fear; to take the colorfrom, whiten.116501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    }
  },
  "Chapter 14": {
    "326": {
      "Question": "6.326.At the beginning of the ceremony, the high school band ______the arrival of the graduates by playing the alma mater loudly andwith enthusiasm.",
      "a": { "option": "decried", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "heralded",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "permeated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "conjured",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "thwarted",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. To herald (v.) is to proclaim or announce; to foreshadow."
    },
    "327": {
      "Question": "7.327.Although Sophie was afraid of heights, she seemed to have no______ about driving over bridges.Chapter 14",
      "a": {
        "option": "enormity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "qualms", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "imminence",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "resurrection",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "severity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. A qualm (n.) is a sudden or disturbing feeling."
    },
    "328": {
      "Question": "8.328.I will write a rough draft of the proposal, and then you can edit itfor any ______ material so that it is as convincing and concise aspossible.",
      "a": {
        "option": "grandiose",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "incontrovertible",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "extraneous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "abysmal", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "pensive", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "c. Extraneous (adj.) means not vital or essential; not pertinent orrelevant; coming from the outside or an outside source."
    },
    "329": {
      "Question": "9.329.I had to call the repairman because the washing machine was off______\u2014it began making terrible sounds and failed to clean the",
      "c": {
        "option": "prevision",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "detriment",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "preferment",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "kilter", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "quandary",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Kilter (n.) is order or good condition."
    },
    "330": {
      "Question": "0.330.Minnie \ufb01nally ______ to her sister\u2019s constant barrage of questions",
      "a": {
        "option": "reiterated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "succumbed",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "seceded", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "reneged", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "retaliated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. To succumb (v.) means to give in, cease to resist."
    },
    "331": {
      "Question": "1.331.The meeting is ______; everyone must attend.118",
      "a": {
        "option": "palatable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "compulsory",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "reciprocal",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "resilient",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "ancillary",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Compulsory (adj.) means obligatory, mandatory, required."
    },
    "332": {
      "Question": "2.332.Through the ______ act of volunteering, it is possible to make a",
      "d": {
        "option": "rapacious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "dilatory",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "insurmountable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "diligent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "noble", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "e. Noble (adj.) means having high, sel\ufb02ess moral standards; ofexcellent character."
    },
    "333": {
      "Question": "3.333.The proposed design includes many ______ features that are notfunctional and can be eliminated to cut costs.",
      "a": { "option": "jovial", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "germane", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "kinetic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "nonchalant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "extrinsic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. Extrinsic (adj.) means not forming an essential part of a thing,extraneous; originating from the outside, external."
    },
    "334": {
      "Question": "4.334.Carly\u2019s ______ spending on shoes and clothing caused her parentsfor college.",
      "a": {
        "option": "monotypic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "inconsistent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "perfunctory",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "immoderate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "specious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Immoderate (adj.) means excessive or extreme; exceedingreasonable limits."
    },
    "335": {
      "Question": "5.335.The cop was in a ______: Should he chase the criminal or help thevictim?",
      "a": {
        "option": "quandary",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "litany", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "tatter", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "discord", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "plethora",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. A quandary (n.) is a dif\ufb01cult situation."
    },
    "336": {
      "Question": "6.336.The professor studied the ______ physics of ballet dancers and",
      "e": {
        "option": "monotonous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "creditable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "kinetic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "symbolic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "prevalent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Kinetic (adj.) means pertaining to motion or caused by motion."
    },
    "337": {
      "Question": "7.337.Kyle was able to ______ the dif\ufb01culties of an uncooperative staff,present the report to the client.",
      "a": {
        "option": "surmount",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "dismount",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "retract", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "expel", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "intercede",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. To surmount (v.) means to overcome by force of will."
    },
    "338": {
      "Question": "8.338.Philbert\u2019s ______ manner \ufb01t in well with the atmosphere of theposh country club.",
      "a": {
        "option": "untoward",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "riotous", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "mundane", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "salacious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "urbane", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "e. Urbane (adj.) means characterized by re\ufb01ned manners; elegantor sophisticated."
    },
    "339": {
      "Question": "9.339.Elian tried his ______ on the wrong person, and it has \ufb01nallylanded him in jail.120",
      "a": {
        "option": "clemency",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "jocularity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "calamity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "obsolescence",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "chicanery",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. Chicanery (n.) is trickery or sophistry used to deceive someone(especially to extract money)."
    },
    "340": {
      "Question": "0.340.There were several ______ buildings on the street, making itof\ufb01ce.",
      "d": { "option": "zealous", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": {
        "option": "nondescript",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "transient",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "impervious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "impressionable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Nondescript (adj.) means lacking any distinctive characteristics.124501 Sentence Completion Questions125"
    },
    "341": {
      "Question": "1.341.In\ufb02ated by his fans\u2019 ______, Evan lost sense of his small-townroots and began traveling with an entourage.",
      "a": {
        "option": "inconstancy",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "insolence",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "haughtiness",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "sufferance",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "idolatry",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. Idolatry (n.) is excessive reverence or adoration; the worship ofidols."
    },
    "342": {
      "Question": "2.342.To ______ a congressional bill, the president must use his of\ufb01cialseal on all documents.",
      "a": { "option": "nullify", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "patronize",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "victimize",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "ratify", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "mollify", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "d. To ratify (v.) means to make valid."
    },
    "343": {
      "Question": "3.343.The drama workshop\u2019s efforts ______ in the \ufb01nal production of aplay written, directed, and acted by the students for the entireschool.",
      "a": {
        "option": "\ufb01nalized",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "languished",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "teemed", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "discerned",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "culminated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. To culminate (v.) is to come to completion, end; to reach thehighest point or degree, climax."
    },
    "344": {
      "Question": "4.344.There is no way around it: plagiarism is ______ to thievery.",
      "a": {
        "option": "tantamount",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "apathetic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "fatuous", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "unscrupulous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "indecisive",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Tantamount (adj.) means equal to; having equal or equivalentvalue in terms of seriousness."
    },
    "345": {
      "Question": "5.345.For ______ deeds during her mission overseas, Tyesha was",
      "a": { "option": "inept", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "valorous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "erroneous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "malodorous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "benign", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "b. Valorous (adj.) means courageous, valiant."
    },
    "346": {
      "Question": "6.346.Adam read the employee manual so that he might ______ himselfwith his new responsibilities at the company.",
      "a": {
        "option": "relinquish",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "synthesize",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "orient", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "validate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "motivate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. To orient (v.) means to acquaint (oneself) with the existingsituation or environment; determine one\u2019s position withreference to new ideas."
    },
    "347": {
      "Question": "7.347.I am ______ of the problems that this solution will cause, but I still",
      "b": {
        "option": "cognizant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "innocuous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "precipitous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "reminiscent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "belligerent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Cognizant (adj.) means fully knowledgeable or informed,conscious, aware."
    },
    "348": {
      "Question": "8.348.The spectacular presentation by a rainforest adventurer ______Simon with the desire to travel to South America to see the junglesfor himself.122",
      "a": {
        "option": "disheartened",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "inhibited",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "imbued", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "reconstituted",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "abhorred",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. To imbue (v.) is to inspire or pervade with ideas or feelings; tosaturate with color; to permeate."
    },
    "349": {
      "Question": "9.349.When the senator\u2019s popularity suffered in the polls, he ______ his",
      "d": {
        "option": "detracted",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "recanted",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "pulverized",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "enveloped",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "extenuated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. To recant (v.) means to renounce formally; to withdraw a formerbelief as erroneous."
    },
    "350": {
      "Question": "0.350.Because of the ______ of reliable information, Quentin\u2019s reportwas comprised mostly of speculation.",
      "a": { "option": "dearth", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "diatribe",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "myriad", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "juxtaposition",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "tirade", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "a. Dearth (n.) means a severe shortage or scarce supply, especiallyof food; a lack of, insuf\ufb01cient quantity.501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    }
  },
  "Chapter 15": {
    "351": {
      "Question": "1.351.Teachers should not only be knowledgeable but also ______;students should feel comfortable approaching them with questionsor problems.",
      "a": {
        "option": "wheedling",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "patronizing",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "laconic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "affable", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "frugal", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "d. Affable (adj.) means easy and pleasant to speak to, approachable;friendly, warm, gracious."
    },
    "352": {
      "Question": "2.352.The pain medication Kristy received after surgery offered relief;however, the overwhelming feeling of ______ was an unexpectedside effect, and she didn\u2019t like being groggy.Chapter 15",
      "a": {
        "option": "extortion",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "compellation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "acquisition",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "af\ufb01rmation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "lethargy",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. Lethargy (n.) is the state of drowsiness or sluggish inactivity."
    },
    "353": {
      "Question": "3.353.The ski lodge had a window that looked out upon a beautifulmountain ______.",
      "a": { "option": "vista", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "melee", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "fray", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "foray", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "frieze", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "a. Vista (n.) means a view or prospect."
    },
    "354": {
      "Question": "4.354.The palace\u2019s great hall was rich in history and splendor, the wallshung with ______ tapestries.",
      "a": {
        "option": "melli\ufb02uous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "malleable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "prudent", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "illusive",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "ornate", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." }
    },
    "355": {
      "Question": "5.355.After weeks of heavy rains, the earth gave way; mud and trees______ down the mountain swallowing cars and houses in their path.",
      "a": {
        "option": "ascended",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "inculcated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "aspersed",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "hurtled", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "entreated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. To hurtle (v.) is to rush with great speed; to move violently withgreat noise; to \ufb02ing forcefully."
    },
    "356": {
      "Question": "6.356.The ______ butter had been left in the refrigerator for years.",
      "a": {
        "option": "complacent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "scandalous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "riveting",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "dire", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "rancid", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "e. Rancid (adj.) means rotten or putrid."
    },
    "357": {
      "Question": "7.357.Several weeks of extremely hot, dry weather ______ the land, soinstead of rowing across a river, we walked across a cracked,parched riverbed.128",
      "a": {
        "option": "oscillated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "desiccated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "subverted",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "coalesced",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "thwarted",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. To desiccate (v.) means to dry out thoroughly, become dry; tomake dry, dull, or lifeless."
    },
    "358": {
      "Question": "8.358.The pitcher\u2019s ______ workout regimen was the most grueling of allhis teammates, and he never took a day off.",
      "a": { "option": "Spartan", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "spasmodic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "exclusive",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "turgid", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "truculent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Spartan (adj.) means rigorously severe (from the Greek city-state Sparta known for its austere and rigid lifestyle); marked bystrict self-discipline; characteristically simple or frugal."
    },
    "359": {
      "Question": "9.359.Ethan\u2019s responses when he spoke on the telephone were ______",
      "a": {
        "option": "receptive",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "laconic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "uncanny", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "suave", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "ponderous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Laconic (adj.) means curt, concise, but expressing much in a fewwords; brief and to the point."
    },
    "360": {
      "Question": "0.360.I was bored with the ______ conversation of my roommates andlonged for some intellectual stimulation.",
      "a": {
        "option": "egregious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "pronounced",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "vapid", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "intriguing",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "exonerating",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. Vapid (adj.) means dull, lacking life, sprit or substance; tedious."
    },
    "361": {
      "Question": "1.361.Ned\u2019s fear was ______ as he watched the 60-foot waves approachhis little boat.",
      "a": { "option": "futile", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "genteel", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "innovative",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "palpable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "detrimental",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Palpable (adj.) means tangible, noticeable; easily perceived anddetected."
    },
    "362": {
      "Question": "2.362.Moving swiftly and gracefully through the backyard, the catsuddenly ______ when she hit the thorny bush.",
      "a": {
        "option": "recoiled",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "recuperated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "invigorated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "fabricated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "throttled",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. To recoil (v.) means to jump back suddenly."
    },
    "363": {
      "Question": "3.363.Although others were fooled by \u201cDoctor\u201d Winston\u2019s speech, Lilyknew him for what he was: a(n) ______.",
      "a": { "option": "panacea", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "charlatan",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "prevarication",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "accolade",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "primadonna",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. A charlatan (n.) is someone who makes elaborate, fraudulentclaims to having certain skills or knowledge; a quack, imposter,fraud."
    },
    "364": {
      "Question": "4.364.The task of building the cabin was a ______ one, but Rob was upto the challenge.",
      "a": {
        "option": "laborious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "venerable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "archaic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "cynical", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "unbiased",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Laborious (adj.) means characterized by hard work, exertion, orperseverance.501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    },
    "365": {
      "Question": "5.365.After the neighbor\u2019s stereo woke her up for the \ufb01fth night in a row,Brenda felt ______ to complain.",
      "a": {
        "option": "impelled",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "rebuked", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "augmented",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "implicated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "destined",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. To impel (v.) is to motivate; push or drive forward; propel."
    },
    "366": {
      "Question": "6.366.Carter is writing a letter of recommendation that I can include inmy ______ for prospective employers.",
      "a": {
        "option": "denunciation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "panacea", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "dossier", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "incantation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "restitution",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. A dossier (n.) is a collection of papers giving detailed informationabout a particular person or subject."
    },
    "367": {
      "Question": "7.367.______ laughter came from the upstairs apartment where Trangwas having a graduation party.130",
      "a": {
        "option": "Scurrilous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "Deleterious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "Fatuous", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "Uproarious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "Malicious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Uproarious (adj.) means noisy."
    },
    "368": {
      "Question": "8.368.In the middle of his eloquent ______, the audience suddenly brokeinto applause.",
      "a": { "option": "ovation", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "oration", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "inclination",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "provocation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "illusion",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. An oration (n.) is a formal speech for a special occasion."
    },
    "369": {
      "Question": "9.369.I like the ______ style of these essays; they make complex issues",
      "a": {
        "option": "colloquial",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "obsolete",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "pristine",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "exacting",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "furtive", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "a. Colloquial (adj.) means characteristic of informal spokenlanguage or conversation; conversational."
    },
    "370": {
      "Question": "0.370.A diamond ring is the ______ symbol of love and affection.",
      "a": {
        "option": "precocious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "fugacious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "supplemental",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "quintessential",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "barbarous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Quintessential (adj.) is the best and purest part of a thing; themost typical example of a thing."
    },
    "371": {
      "Question": "1.371.Allen\u2019s ______ distanced him from his family, but he was stillunwilling to apologize.",
      "a": {
        "option": "regeneration",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "contingency",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "equivalence",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "impenitence",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "innovation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Impenitence (n.) is the trait of refusing to repent; unwilling toshow regret for wrongdoing."
    },
    "372": {
      "Question": "2.372.Nothing will ______ my memory of the night we \ufb01rst met; theimages are forever burned in my mind.",
      "a": { "option": "appease", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "undulate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "inculcate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "efface", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "truncate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. To efface (v.) means to rub out, erase; to cause to dim or makeindistinct; to make or conduct oneself inconspicuously."
    },
    "373": {
      "Question": "3.373.With the curtains drawn back, the room was ______ with warmsunlight.",
      "a": {
        "option": "recessed",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "intruded",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "suffused",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "belied", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "taut", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "c. To suffuse (v.) means to cover or \ufb01ll the surface of, as in to \ufb01llwith light."
    },
    "374": {
      "Question": "4.374.The devastating drought forced the ______ tribes of the rainforestto leave their homes and venture into the modern world.",
      "a": {
        "option": "indigenous",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "puritanical",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "indigent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "imminent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "muni\ufb01cent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Indigenous (adj.) means originating or being native to a speci\ufb01cregion or country; also inherent or natural."
    },
    "375": {
      "Question": "5.375.Jason\u2019s ______ approach to management included narrowing thesalary gap between the CEOs and of\ufb01ce workers.132",
      "a": { "option": "stoic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "apathetic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "utilitarian",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "endemic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "proactive",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. Utilitarian (adj.) means related to the ethical doctrine thatactions are right because they are useful or bene\ufb01cial to thegreatest number of people.134501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    }
  },
  "Chapter 16": {
    "376": {
      "Question": "6.376.If people continue to ______ the rainforests, soon they will",
      "d": { "option": "neglect", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": {
        "option": "dominate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "frolic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "laminate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "provoke", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "d. To neglect (v.) means to be careless about; to fail to care for or todo; to be remiss about."
    },
    "377": {
      "Question": "7.377.My parents always seem to worry and ______ more about moneywhen tax season is approaching.Chapter 16",
      "a": {
        "option": "proximate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "quibble", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "supplicate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "dabble", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "alienate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. To quibble (v.) means to \ufb01nd fault or criticize for petty reasons."
    },
    "378": {
      "Question": "8.378.While the king and the members of his court lived in the mostopulent luxury, the peasants in his kingdom lived in the most______ poverty.",
      "a": { "option": "abject", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "incessant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "relinquished",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "erratic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "lugubrious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Abject (adj.) means wretched, degraded, debased; of the mostcontemptible or miserable kind; showing utter resignation orhumiliation, groveling, servile."
    },
    "379": {
      "Question": "9.379.Samantha had an ______ trust in her grandfather, who was anhonorable man and kind to everyone he met.",
      "a": {
        "option": "implicit",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "insecure",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "irreverent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "irresolute",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "astringent",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Implicit (adj.) means unquestioning or trusting without doubt;understood rather than directly stated; implied."
    },
    "380": {
      "Question": "0.380.Antonello searched the forest around his campsite for small",
      "b": { "option": "kindle", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "a": {
        "option": "sti\ufb02e",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "suppress",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "dissipate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "prohibit",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. Kindle (v.) means to cause to burn with \ufb02ames; to ignite; to seton \ufb01re."
    },
    "381": {
      "Question": "1.381.Although I meant it as a compliment, Zander ______ my remark as136",
      "a": {
        "option": "construed",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "eradicated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "truncated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "permeated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "redacted",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. To construe (v.) is to interpret or understand; to make sense of,explain the meaning of."
    },
    "382": {
      "Question": "2.382.The sailor\u2019s ______ complexion bespoke his many sunny days atthe lookout post.",
      "a": { "option": "swarthy", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "syncopated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "pallid", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": { "option": "wan", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "pasty", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "a. Swarthy (adj.) means having a dark hue, especially a dark orsunburned complexion."
    },
    "383": {
      "Question": "3.383.Tanya is a ______ person, trusted by all who know her.",
      "a": { "option": "porous", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "voracious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "spurious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "specious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "veracious",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. Veracious (adj.) means truthful, honest; habitually disposed tospeak the truth."
    },
    "384": {
      "Question": "4.384.After the third relative was hired to an upper-level position, severalpeople quit the company, claiming that ______ caused a decline in",
      "e": {
        "option": "nepotism",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": { "option": "carrion", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "explicitness",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "skepticism",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "devotion",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. Nepotism (n.) is favoritism for kin when conferring jobs, of\ufb01ces,or privileges."
    },
    "385": {
      "Question": "5.385.Genevieve\u2019s stunning debut performance at the city opera has",
      "e": {
        "option": "accolades",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "antipathy",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "insinuations",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "destitution",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "lamentations",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. An accolade (n.) is an award or special acknowledgementsignifying approval or distinction."
    },
    "386": {
      "Question": "6.386.The shaggy neon couch was a(n) ______ in the conservative room",
      "d": {
        "option": "reiteration",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "incongruity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "insinuation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "temerity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "intonation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Incongruity (n.) is the quality of being inappropriate orunbecoming; not consistent in character."
    },
    "387": {
      "Question": "7.387.Harris tried to ______ his fear of \ufb02ying when he boarded theplane, but he could not curb his anxiety.",
      "a": {
        "option": "accelerate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "expound", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "maximize",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "employ", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "repress", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "e. To repress (v.) means to keep under or restrain; to curb orsubdue.501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    },
    "388": {
      "Question": "8.388.Gabi found that whenever she was confused about an idea or issue,writing about it would help ______ her true feelings.",
      "a": {
        "option": "vacillate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "elucidate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "wheedle", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "deprecate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "indoctrinate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "confusion or ambiguity."
    },
    "389": {
      "Question": "9.389.After the powerful windstorm, Marie discovered a splintered andfallen tree limb had ______ the vinyl lining of her swimming pool.",
      "a": {
        "option": "extenuated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "calculated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "retaliated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "lacerated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "curtailed",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. To lacerate (v.) is to rip, tear, or mangle."
    },
    "390": {
      "Question": "0.390.Johnny\u2019s good behavior in class yesterday was ______ by his",
      "d": {
        "option": "mandated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": { "option": "abated", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": { "option": "negated", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "reiterated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "nominated",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "b. To negate (v.) means to nullify, invalidate, or deny."
    },
    "391": {
      "Question": "1.391.Jason and Joshua made ______ plans to meet in the cafeteria tostudy for the test, provided Jason\u2019s class ended on time.138",
      "a": {
        "option": "beguiling",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "tenuous", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "assured", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "tentative",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "promotional",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Tentative (adj.) means provisional or uncertain; not \ufb01xed or set."
    },
    "392": {
      "Question": "2.392.The professor\u2019s lectures were \ufb01lled with excessive ______, lastingmuch longer than was necessary to convey his ideas.",
      "a": {
        "option": "verbiage",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "herbage", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "maliciousness",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "portent", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "intrigue",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Verbiage (n.) means the use of many words without necessity."
    },
    "393": {
      "Question": "3.393.Ming\u2019s blatant lie revealed that he suffered no ______ about being",
      "d": {
        "option": "evanescence",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "compunction",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "repudiation",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "vindication",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "veracity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Compunction (n.) means a feeling of uneasiness or regret causedby a sense of guilt, remorse; a pang of conscience at the thoughtor act of committing a misdeed."
    },
    "394": {
      "Question": "4.394.Diane, always teasing, was known for her ______ , but as a result,nobody knew when to take her seriously.",
      "a": {
        "option": "jocularity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "servitude",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "logic", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "austerity",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "inclemency",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "a. Jocularity (n.) is the state of being jocular, which is characterizedby joking or jesting."
    },
    "395": {
      "Question": "5.395.\u201cAbsolute power corrupts absolutely,\u201d said Haines. \u201cThere is nosuch thing as a(n) ______ who is not a corrupt and cruel ruler.\u201d",
      "a": {
        "option": "imbroglio",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "pedant", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": { "option": "despot", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "agnostic",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "archetype",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "c. A despot (n.) is someone who rules with absolute power; adictator or tyrant."
    },
    "396": {
      "Question": "6.396.During his ______ in of\ufb01ce the mayor made several controversial",
      "d": {
        "option": "\ufb02out",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "a": {
        "option": "treatise",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "integration",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "teem", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": { "option": "tenure", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "e. Tenure (n.) means the term during which a thing is held; oftenused in connection with career positions."
    },
    "397": {
      "Question": "7.397.Recovering from the tragedy, Helena found the ______ sunrisereassuring, as it gave her something to rely on each and everymorning.",
      "a": { "option": "hidden", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "b": {
        "option": "clairvoyant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "cognizant",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": { "option": "deft", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "e": {
        "option": "quotidian",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "e. Quotidian (adj.) means occurring or returning daily."
    },
    "398": {
      "Question": "8.398.Flaws in Claire\u2019s opponent\u2019s chess game showed him to be ______,",
      "a": {
        "option": "predatory",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "indistinguishable",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": { "option": "ornery", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "d": {
        "option": "vincible",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "resolute",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "subdued."
    },
    "399": {
      "Question": "9.399.The ad didn\u2019t mention a speci\ufb01c salary; it just said \u201ccompensation______ with experience.\u201d",
      "a": {
        "option": "compulsory",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": {
        "option": "manifest",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "c": {
        "option": "proli\ufb01c",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "commensurate",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": {
        "option": "precluded",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "Answer": "d. Commensurate (adj.) means corresponding in size, degree, orextent; proportionate."
    },
    "400": {
      "Question": "0.400.The ______ she felt for shopping made it impossible for her towalk by a sale window without stopping.140",
      "a": {
        "option": "providence",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "b": { "option": "blunder", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "c": {
        "option": "omission",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "d": {
        "option": "repulsion",
        "meaning": "No meaning found for the word."
      },
      "e": { "option": "estrus", "meaning": "No meaning found for the word." },
      "Answer": "e. An estrus (n.) is an irresistible impulse or passion.142501 Sentence Completion Questions"
    }
  }
}
